<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sinner/Saint</title>
    <description>&quot;Every saint has a past and every sinner has a future.&quot; - Oscar Wilde
</description>
    <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.ryanstraits.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 17:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 17:44:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Things</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;dfdssdfds&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 11:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2017/02/17/new-things.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2017/02/17/new-things.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Growing Up/Getting Older&amp;#58; Part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though you&amp;#39;re always going to have the contrarians who are all too happy to proclaim, &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;m 33 and I feel great!&amp;quot; Compared to your pre-33-year-old self, however, you objectively feel like crap. You just don&amp;#39;t know it because, well, that&amp;#39;s the fun thing about aging: it slowly sneaks up on you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year your body is going to suck just a little bit more. It&amp;#39;s kind of a verifiable fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, by 33 your body has already started breaking down. They say that your &lt;a href=&quot;http://io9.com/5176536/your-brain-starts-deteriorating-by-age-27-say-neuroscientists&quot; target=_blank&gt;age 27 year&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mindpowernews.com/BrainPeaks.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;statistically&lt;/a&gt; when your &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/health/7945569.stm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mind&amp;#39;s cognitive ability&lt;/a&gt; starts to trend downward. What MIT calls your &lt;a href=&quot;http://newsoffice.mit.edu/2015/brain-peaks-at-different-ages-0306?utm_content=buffer29268&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;fluid intelligence&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; actually peaks at little earlier...at age 20. In turn, your body&amp;#39;s metabolism starts it&amp;#39;s long arc of decline at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mensfitness.com/weight-loss/burn-fat-fast/ask-mens-fitness-what-age-does-persons-metabolism-start-significantly-slow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;around age 24&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s not fair,&amp;quot; you might think, &amp;quot;20 is too young to start declining.&amp;quot; And I think anyone over 20 would agree with you. But if you step back and look over the entire pantheon of human history, 20 is right at the cusp of our collective median age. 200 years ago the average lifespan was &lt;em&gt;barely&lt;/em&gt; 40 years. In that respect, 20-year-olds should be having mid-life crises and buying red convertibles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And all before they can legally drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The older I get the more apparent it is that 21st century bodies just haven&amp;#39;t caught up to humanity&amp;#39;s expanding life expectancies yet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are increasingly outliving our own functional lifespan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know that we begin aging the moment we&amp;#39;re born. Already my 2-year-old daughter has creases in her skin from lots of giggles and too much sun at the kiddie pool. We just don&amp;#39;t pay close attention to our bodies&amp;#39; aging until we&amp;#39;re older. When those creases become more prominent, when the weight is a little harder to keep off and when our hair starts letting go a little easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s not until these mid-life epiphanies that we begin to consider that our lives might actually be finite just like everyone else&amp;#39;s. I mean, how many times do you really think about dying before you hit 30? Maybe you had a near-death or religious experience, lost a loved one, or had a moment of clarity at your high school graduation. On the whole, though, we all plan our lives as if they&amp;#39;re going to last forever. Somehow we&amp;#39;re going to rise above it if we just ignore it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s only when your butt starts to sag a little that you snap back to reality: &amp;quot;Oh yeah, this body is probably only going to live another 50 years or so.&amp;quot; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Finding Fitness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve always been pretty keen on working out and trying to at least maintain a healthy weight. I kept up pretty well with it through my 20&amp;#39;s. There was safety in the routine of it. I also think I inherited an irrational--though maybe healthy?--fear of getting overweight. So, my thinking was that if I could just stay a step ahead, I&amp;#39;d be able to head off my metabolism before it completely dropped off the cliff. This really just meant that I flailed my arms &amp;amp; legs on an elliptical in my parents&amp;#39; basement roughly 3 times a week. It worked for me only because I didn&amp;#39;t &lt;em&gt;completely&lt;/em&gt; hate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/TourDeBBQ1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cycling + BBQ&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A revelation occurred to me in the summer of 2009, however, when I got into cycling. I&amp;#39;m not much of a runner--or an athlete, for that matter--so the simplicity of biking was something I embraced wholeheartedly. It was something I was finally good at. I bought a nice bike and while getting fit for it, the trainer commented that I had a nice pedal stroke. A nice pedal stroke! Dammit, I was &lt;em&gt;made&lt;/em&gt; for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I went for it full speed and racked up a lot of miles in my first few years. I took a hiatus after I moved from the expansive Ohio countryside to Kansas City and it&amp;#39;s congested suburban streets. Then in 2011, I worked up the nerve and started wading through traffic and working my way back in to it. It was true love. I passed 2,000 miles on my bike in 2012 after nearly 3 seasons of riding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then my daughter was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/audrey-birth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Proud Papa&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those without children: Basically, the birth of your first child is this unalterable, drastic upheaval in whatever form of a priority structure you once had. And one that you&amp;#39;re pretty certain you&amp;#39;ll never bounce back from. Up is down and down is less sleep. Oh, sleep. How you can&amp;#39;t wait until they&amp;#39;re asleep! (I&amp;#39;ll talk more on this in Part 2).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over two years in, I&amp;#39;d like to say that my workout regimen has normalized since Audrey&amp;#39;s birth, but that just isn&amp;#39;t a reality:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bicycle rides in 2012 alone: 53.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rides since Audrey&amp;#39;s birth in 2012: 30 and counting...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m getting back into it but I&amp;#39;ve had to adjust expectations. We got a gym membership recently at a local community center. Going as a family has helped. But there just isn&amp;#39;t enough time in the day. Kids take up so much of it, and deservedly so. It&amp;#39;s hard work but I doubt anyone with kids would trade them for anything. Even our fitness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a younger man, I looked sideways at parents that let themselves go after they had kids. &amp;quot;Convenient excuse&amp;quot;, this all-knowing punk thought. &amp;quot;Just you wait&amp;quot;, they&amp;#39;d say back to me in a look that didn&amp;#39;t require saying anything at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you break my day down now, the time I spend with my daughter overlaps nearly completely with the time I used to spend cycling or working out. And I&amp;#39;m OK with that. It just means I have to work a little harder to find something else to steal time from. Usually, it&amp;#39;s from television. And from typing up blog posts such as this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really, when I get a chance to work out, I&amp;#39;m also working out for Audrey. The better shape I&amp;#39;m in today means I&amp;#39;m going to be much a happier and healthier dad tomorrow. And eventually, a happier and healthier grandpa for her to take care of somewhere down the line. All the more reason to hit the bike and the gym with whatever waning moments I have left in the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/audrey-faces.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Goofballs&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s hard to admit this to teenager-me or 20-year-old-me, but an extra 10-15 pounds just isn&amp;#39;t that big of a deal at this stage of the game. And you care less about those extra pounds the older you get. That&amp;#39;s just life. There are plenty more important things to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#39;s what I think when I look at parents now. I commiserate. I get it. This stage of life is rough. It&amp;#39;s a boxing match with entropy. And the body blows only hit harder and harder the older you get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Middling Age&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aging is weird. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your 30&amp;#39;s reveal that--like some cruel plot twist early in the 2nd act--your body has just been out to betray you all along. It&amp;#39;s slowly been switching from your side to the one of some unknowable, unrepentant force of evil. And no matter how hard you try to coax and convince it, it&amp;#39;s just not coming back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things that you used to enjoy--like sleeping in, eating, showering, and pick-up games of any sport--now become reflections on your fragility. I can&amp;#39;t sleep-in past 8AM now without my back feeling like it&amp;#39;s going to dislodge a vertebrae. Eating becomes a tally of how many pounds a meal will add to my waistline and how many miles are required to run/bike them off. Showering enters a whole new level of creepiness now as you horrifically gaze in the mirror at this saggier, hairier, alternate-reality version of your 20 year-old-self staring back at you. And this happens everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, well, you just &lt;em&gt;hurt&lt;/em&gt; after any and all prolonged periods of activity now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You hurt a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But obviously, there is a richness to this stage of aging that I&amp;#39;ve been skirting. For all the fresh wrinkles, new aches and extra pounds, there&amp;#39;s an airy plateau of transcendence that can only be reached once you crest that first hill of your 30&amp;#39;s. A plateau that gives you a clearer view of your life and how little of it you actually have left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve made it this far and my body is still intact. I have the majority of my hair, more brown than greys and still some bounce in my step. I managed to snag a wife before I hit 30, so really, there&amp;#39;s no one left to impress (don&amp;#39;t tell her that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do I have to worry about? Just squeezing every ounce of life out of this old thing that I can in the next 50 years or so, that&amp;#39;s all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s not rosy but I think having a firm grasp on your finality is a good thing. It makes you try harder, push deeper, and commit more fully. You are much less likely to half-ass your way through life when you have an achy back or a creaky knee constantly reminding you that your body is trending in a downward direction. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier I noted an MIT study that claimed our &amp;quot;fluid intelligence&amp;quot; peaked at age 20. If you actually clicked the link and read on from the first few paragraphs, you&amp;#39;d realize that I wasn&amp;#39;t entirely truthful with what I reported back. Oops, creative license.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, some of our cognitive abilities peak when we&amp;#39;re younger, but many more are still ascending upwards through our 30&amp;#39;s and even into our 50&amp;#39;s and 60&amp;#39;s. Facial recognition and visual short term memory both peak in your early 30&amp;#39;s, says the MIT study. Our vocabulary and the mental skills needed to evaluate other&amp;#39;s emotional states peak in our 40&amp;#39;s and 50&amp;#39;s. Well, that&amp;#39;s certainly something to look forward to!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And really, it makes sense. My mind doesn&amp;#39;t feel all that old. In fact, it&amp;#39;s still on point. Our 30&amp;#39;s are the years to take advantage of our superior mental acuity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Middle age is the unique period of life when you will actually know more than both your kids &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; your parents. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;re probably not going to be more &amp;quot;with it&amp;quot; mentally than you are in your 30&amp;#39;s. This is a gift, and we would do well to take advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I know there will be folks several years my senior that will no doubt scoff at a 33-year-old complaining--and writing so darn long--about feeling old. I get it. I know I have plenty of aging, aches and probably pounds left ahead of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I think if you polled a few individuals down the road a ways, and asked them to recall what birthday they first started to feel the full force of aging, I&amp;#39;m pretty certain the majority would agree:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;33 is definitely when you start to feel &lt;em&gt;old&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Part 2: Soul&amp;quot; will be coming your way in a month or so. Until then feel free to dig into the &lt;a href=&quot;/archive&quot;&gt;Archive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2015/07/27/growing-up-getting-older-part1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2015/07/27/growing-up-getting-older-part1.html</guid>
        
        <category>now-that-im-older</category>
        
        <category>my-body-is-a-cage</category>
        
        <category>ride-on-right-on</category>
        
        <category>fambly</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Growing Up/Getting Older&amp;#58; Intro</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Or, a few thoughts on living in this very body, soul &amp;amp; spirit after a mere 33 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Preface&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Friendship is born at that moment when one person says to another: &amp;quot;What! You too? I thought I was the only one.&amp;quot; - C.S. Lewis &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What follows is a treatise, of sorts, on my experiences growing older and nearing middle age. It&amp;#39;s part memoir, part advice column, part commentary, part confessional, part gag reel. With these posts I&amp;#39;m by no means claiming expertise on the subjects contained within, far from it actually. I&amp;#39;m just wanting to share some of the things I&amp;#39;ve personally discovered along the way. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had originally intended to publish a shorter version of this post around my 33rd birthday last fall. However, as my thoughts gained structure, the scope quickly expanded--as broad topics have a tendency of doing with me--and so I&amp;#39;ve broken this whole mess down into three more manageable posts (Body, Soul and Spirit). You&amp;#39;re free to ingest any or all of them with however many grains of salt (or strong drinks) you require.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;#39;t meant to be a conversation starter, though you&amp;#39;re more than welcome to chime in. It&amp;#39;s more an exercise in collating and fastening down a few thoughts, realizations and revelations that have been jangling around in my head for the last few years. It&amp;#39;s me attempting to make sense of my journey so far and looking forward to the journey ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I also hope that you&amp;#39;re encouraged by this sort of candor and honesty in the same way I am. I&amp;#39;m talking about those refreshing moments when someone speaks to a thought or an experience that you have also had at one point or another. To know that you&amp;#39;re not alone in your oddities and idiosyncrasies, but that you instead share some basic sense of commonality and commiseration with the entire human race. I pray these posts give you at least one of those moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because in the end, we&amp;#39;re all just growing old together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Intro: The Age Of The Lord&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned 33 this past November. It&amp;#39;s an age some of us can probably remember our parents turning but never dedicated much forethought to becoming ourselves. When you&amp;#39;re young, it&amp;#39;s just a far-off point on the horizon. It&amp;#39;s Marty McFly watching his dorky-dad-self in the &lt;em&gt;distant&lt;/em&gt; future of 2015. It&amp;#39;s that boring mid-point between &amp;quot;younger&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;older&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your thirties can certainly be irrelevant if you let them be. But 33 seemed to strike a certain significance with me, which I suppose is due to the permeation of Christianity throughout my childhood. Those of us who attended Sunday School will recall that 33 was the age that Jesus completed his earthly ministry and died on the cross. A somewhat random factoid about the life of Christ that despite all the importance tied to numbers in the Bible, doesn&amp;#39;t seem to mean all that much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now that I&amp;#39;ve actually reached the age of the Lord myself, it feels like the right time to ask the question: Just what was the deal with only living 33 years? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it was dying on the cross he wanted to do, he could&amp;#39;ve accomplished that after only, say, 18 or 20 years, to be humane. If he wanted to do all the miracles he could or make as many disciples as possible, why not live longer? What was so special about 33?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#39;t do any deep diving into the scriptures on the significance of the age 33--sorry, this isn&amp;#39;t going to be that kind of post--though many have postulated their own &lt;a href=&quot;https://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20070406181925AA1nBWX&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;theories&lt;/a&gt; on the subject already. Even still, I feel this past birthday of mine has given me a little perspective on just what the Lord&amp;#39;s holy reasoning might&amp;#39;ve been:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, things just start to suck around 33. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It actually starts to suck around 30, honestly, but most of us have the fortitude within us to deny it for a couple of years. 33 is just about when the full weight of middle age sets in. Take pro athletes, for example: when does the level of their game start it&amp;#39;s steepest decline? &lt;a href=&quot;http://deadspin.com/report-troy-polamalu-has-revelation-in-church-retires-1696917787&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pretty darn close to 33.&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;#39;m guessing Jesus didn&amp;#39;t feel so different, divinity and all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, you&amp;#39;re not quite at your mid-life crisis by 33 but you&amp;#39;re starting to feel it slowly creep in. You feel it in your body. In your soul. And in your spirit. You are getting &lt;em&gt;old&lt;/em&gt; and there is no going back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are trade-offs to the downsides of getting older. I doubt any of us past 30 would give back the wisdom we&amp;#39;ve gained since our younger years. We may be quite alright giving back many of the mistakes we&amp;#39;ve made but we certainly wouldn&amp;#39;t ask for a refund on all the valuable lessons we&amp;#39;ve learned from those mistakes. Those of us with kids wouldn&amp;#39;t give them back. Well. Maybe some would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most of us, though, these intangible areas of life only get richer the older you get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you have to think Jesus knew what he was doing when he high-tailed it back to heaven at such a young age, right? &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;ll just do my thing, save the world and then get the heck outta Dodge before I wind up with a wine gut.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take it from the Creator of the carbon-based life-forms we call bodies: it&amp;#39;s pretty much all downhill from 33.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue on to &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/07/27/growing-up-getting-older-part1.html&quot;&gt;Part 1: Body&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2015/07/27/growing-up-getting-older-intro.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2015/07/27/growing-up-getting-older-intro.html</guid>
        
        <category>now-that-im-older</category>
        
        <category>fambly</category>
        
        <category>jesus-etc</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog 3.0</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, here we all are again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every few years, I just need a fresh new start. Usually for me, that means a new blog and an attempt to start writing semi-regularly again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here it is, fresh &amp;amp; squeaky-clean: Blog 3.0. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#39;t promise much more than I have on the last few. Yes, Xanga and Squarespace got me through some formidable years. And I&amp;#39;ve tried &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ryanstraits&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://ryanstraits.svbtle.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Svbtle&lt;/a&gt;, each with varying success. But I ultimately decided it was time to carve out my own little corner of the interweb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the suggestion of my friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Eric&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to give &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jekyll/Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; a shot and so far I&amp;#39;m digging it. It&amp;#39;s a bit more coding than I&amp;#39;ve done in the past, but I&amp;#39;ve enjoyed the learning curve. I also probably spent &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; too much time tweaking this site to my liking from the original &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dirkfabisch/mediator&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Medium-esque&lt;/a&gt; theme that I heisted, but I&amp;#39;m pretty proud of the finished product. Expect more updating to the theme &amp;amp; features as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;ll also see that I ported over all my past blogging adventures to this new site. Yeah, I went there. Xanga &amp;#39;n all. Pretty embarrassing stuff on that old blog, but the &lt;a href=&quot;/2008/03/28/im-a-serial-archivist.html&quot;&gt;serial archivist&lt;/a&gt; in me is pleased to have all of my online writing endeavors now in one, succinct location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, to breathe some fresh content into this new blog of mine, I&amp;#39;m kicking off a 3-part series starting today. A bit of a lofty goal, I know, but one that I&amp;#39;m pretty keen on completing. It&amp;#39;ll be centered around some observations of mine on life after 33 years of living it. Part 1 and a brief intro have already been posted!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Growing Up/Getting Older&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/07/27/growing-up-getting-older-intro.html&quot;&gt;Intro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/07/27/growing-up-getting-older-part1.html&quot;&gt;Part 1: Body&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part 2: Soul (coming roughly Sept. 2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part 3: Spirit (coming roughly Nov. 2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also dive into a few fun little rabbit holes by using the tagging system that I added. Here are a few fun ones to get you started:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tag/xanga&quot;&gt;Xanga&lt;/a&gt; (my old Xanga posts, circa 2003-2007)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tag/squarespace&quot;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; (my old Squarespace posts, circa 2007-2013)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tag/tour-blog&quot;&gt;Tour-Blog&lt;/a&gt; (a blog I kept while on tour with the band State Bird in the Summer of 2007)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2015/07/27/blog-3.0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2015/07/27/blog-3.0.html</guid>
        
        <category>we-laugh-indoors</category>
        
        <category>that-sad-and-holy-glow</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hate Before Love</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have this quirk. I tend to hate things that I wind up falling in love with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It happens a lot with new apps. I think an idea is stupid and write it off, then it comes back around to woo me. Twitter is one example. I &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ryanstraits/statuses/789269312&quot; title=&quot;First Tweet&quot;&gt;signed up in 2008&lt;/a&gt;, but didn&amp;#39;t start using it until 2010. Now it&amp;#39;s the first app I go to on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s happened even more often with music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back around 2000, a good friend wanted me to download &amp;amp; burn him a copy of this new British band he had just heard of. For some reason, I instantly couldn&amp;#39;t stand them. Something about their sound irked me, like they were just sampling The Bends era Radiohead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years later, I heard &amp;quot;In My Place&amp;quot; on a TV show and had to know what band it was. Well, it was obviously Coldplay. I had missed the boat, they were pretty good. After that, I couldn&amp;#39;t get enough. And then I had to get caught up on Parachutes, which everyone was sick of back in 2000. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there was Springsteen. I didn&amp;#39;t have any friends into The Boss, I just hated him on mostly political grounds. I was a fairly heavy conservative back around 2004 and he was prominent in the Democratic opposition to The Iraq War and George W. Bush. Something about his political activism struck me the wrong way, so I wrote him and his American-blue-collar-rock off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to the spring of 2008. I had just started course-correcting myself back to being a moderate. I was beginning to think towards voting for Barack Obama. But it wasn&amp;#39;t anything political that turned me on to The Boss, it was purely a chance musical encounter: I was at a Margaritaville in Myrtle Beach, South Carolina. The cheesiest place you can be, really. I overheard a live version of &amp;quot;Waiting On A Sunny Day&amp;quot; on the restaurant radio. The cheesiest Boss song you could play (though you could debate that award goes to &amp;quot;Cadillac Ranch&amp;quot; just as easily).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something about it hooked me. His live show energy. The huge E-Street sound. Something. I went back to our vacation condo and downloaded every Springsteen album I could. From that moment, I was a Boss fan. He&amp;#39;s become one of my all-time favorite artists. I&amp;#39;ve seen him live twice and hope to again many times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if those were the only two examples of this phenomena, I wouldn&amp;#39;t think much of it. But I could recite similar stories of heavy distaste for many of my favorite bands/artists now: mewithoutYou, Beirut, Broken Social Scene, The National, and on and on. With varying levels of initial distaste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s the strangest thing to me. Maybe I am just too skeptical. Maybe it just  takes a second and a third try to sway me around. And honestly, I can&amp;#39;t tell if that&amp;#39;s a good thing or a bad thing. Maybe it just takes that much more to convince me that something&amp;#39;s worth more than one listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you want to know if you have a really great idea or a hot new sound, let me take a gander. If I don&amp;#39;t like it, you probably have something worthy on your hands there. In the meantime, I&amp;#39;ll just take stock of the things I hate right now and prepare myself for a few years down the road when they&amp;#39;ll be the only thing I talk about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2014/03/23/hate-before-love.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2014/03/23/hate-before-love.html</guid>
        
        <category>dad-rock</category>
        
        <category>that-sad-and-holy-glow</category>
        
        <category>we-laugh-indoors</category>
        
        <category>svbtle</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I Work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you ever happen to catch me on my lunch break, besides munching on some tasty sourdough pretzels, you will most likely find me laboring to get to whatever the RSS equivalent of &amp;quot;Inbox Zero&amp;quot; is on this ever-expanding feed of mine. I, of course, have an elaborate system for how I make my way through the many blogs, tech journals and &amp;quot;what&amp;#39;s new&amp;quot; sites that I like to keep up on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One such ritual requires that I always save my two favorite technology-centered blogs for dead last, &lt;a href=&quot;http://gizmodo.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lifehacker&lt;/a&gt;. They are both excellently curated and seem to always feature articles that pique my interest on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of their more recent features revolves around interviewing &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5967582/im-anthony-casalena-founder-of-squarespace-and-this-is-how-i-work&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;various&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5965839/im-bradford-shellhammer-founder-of-fab-and-this-is-how-i-work&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;movers&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5971940/im-guy-kawasaki-and-this-is-how-i-work&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;shakers&lt;/a&gt; within the tech industry to see what their work setup is like and what keeps them staying productive. I eat this kind of stuff up, like those aforementioned pretzels I suppose, since I&amp;#39;m always looking for ways to become more efficient or keep on task. I&amp;#39;m easily distracted, so sometimes it&amp;#39;s nice to do what I can to eliminate those interruptions or keep them to a minimum. And the great news is, there are A TON of great apps/techniques/what-have-you hitting the interwebs every day that are armed and ready to help fight those distractions right along side me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, since Lifehacker isn&amp;#39;t going to be interviewing lowly ol&amp;#39; me any time soon, I went ahead and decided to interview myself and share some of the tips and tricks I use to keep me pointed in the right direction both at work and at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name:&lt;/strong&gt; Ryan Straits&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Occupation:&lt;/strong&gt; Product Line (Mechanical) Engineer, Marlen International, Overland Park, KS&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Kansas City, MO&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Current computer:&lt;/strong&gt; Lenovo W530 Thinkpad w/ Docking Station &amp;amp; dual 24&amp;quot; displays (Work), 24&amp;quot; iMac (Home)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Current mobile device:&lt;/strong&gt; iPhone 5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What apps/software/tools can&amp;#39;t you live without?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excel. I do just about everything in it and it&amp;#39;s my lifesaver. From budgets to listing out objectives &amp;amp; action items for managing projects, I don&amp;#39;t go a day without using it. I also just started using a pretty great website/app called &lt;a href=&quot;https://workflowy.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Workflowy&lt;/a&gt; to stay organized. It&amp;#39;s helped me get all my thoughts in one place. On the days I&amp;#39;m feeling particularly unfocused, I resort to using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.focusboosterapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Focus Booster&lt;/a&gt;, which is one of the slickest &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.focusboosterapp.com/the-pomodoro-technique&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pomodoro technique&lt;/a&gt; apps that I&amp;#39;ve come across.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For hardware, since Autodesk Inventor is the main program I&amp;#39;m working in all day, my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.3dconnexion.com/products/spacenavigator.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Space Navigator&lt;/a&gt; is essential. It&amp;#39;s any 3D modeler&amp;#39;s best friend. I&amp;#39;m also a big fan of using trackball mice. I have one at home and at work. They&amp;#39;re annoying for the uninitiated but once you start using one, you&amp;#39;ll never go back to traditional mice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Home Screen&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&amp;#39;s your best time-saving shortcut/life hack?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became a much more efficient person the day I discovered that apps like &lt;a href=&quot;http://getpocket.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; exist. I used to get stuck feeling forced to rush through reading articles or websites that I didn&amp;#39;t have time to check out. Pocket allows me to save that stuff for later when I really have the time to dive into them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a more general sense, I am a very big systems guy. I&amp;#39;m fairly forgetful, so I&amp;#39;ve learned to structure menial tasks so that I don&amp;#39;t forget to do them. Ask my wife, I have pretty much the same routine every day. It may seem boring, but it allows my mind to think about all the other things I need to do rather than worry about whether I forgot to brush my teeth or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&amp;#39;s your favorite to-do list manager?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to give Apple&amp;#39;s Reminders it&amp;#39;s best shot since it&amp;#39;s integrated into iOS and OSX so heavily. But it&amp;#39;s annoying sync glitches eventually forced me to start auditioning replacements. I tried several popular choices including &lt;a href=&quot;https://cheddarapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cheddar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.6wunderkinder.com/wunderlist&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wunderlist&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://astrid.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Astrid&lt;/a&gt; but found them all lacking in different ways. I also didn&amp;#39;t want to lay down hard-earned cash for top-rated apps like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.realmacsoftware.com/clear/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Clear&lt;/a&gt; when I knew I could find a decent free one out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I eventually settled on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.any.do/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Any.DO&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s got a pretty slick iOS app and a full-featured Chrome extension to go with it. Since I usually always have Chrome open during the day, Any.DO&amp;#39;s integration with it is priceless. I also like that I can plan out projects using Workflowy and then just select a line item, right-click and add it right to a to-do list in Any.DO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&amp;#39;s your workspace like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to think I keep a pretty clutter-free workspace but I often don&amp;#39;t have as much time as I&amp;#39;d like to keep things in their proper place. If I get done with a certain task near the end of the day and don&amp;#39;t have time to start another I&amp;#39;ll usually use the remaining part of the work day to tidy up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m a big fan of &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5984548/boost-your-productivity-by-adjusting-your-workspaces-lighting-and-temperature&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;natural lighting and an ergonomic environment&lt;/a&gt; and believe that humans are their most productive when they have ample amounts of both. As you can see from the picture below, I don&amp;#39;t get much of either in my current broom closet of an office. However, I am thankful for the 4 walls and door that I do have, though. Since 2005, I have been to 3 different jobs and all 3 were in cubicles. This was my first job back in an office since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be short-lived, however, as my company is relocating to a new facility in Riverside, MO next month. It&amp;#39;s brand new and filled with, you guessed it, cubicles. I&amp;#39;m sure the newness of the office will be great, but I&amp;#39;ll miss the brief year or so that I got to spend in a closed off space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/work-setup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Work&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/home-setup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Home&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you listen to while you work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can usually always find me with at least one earbud in at work. They were (and will be) my only walls in Cubeville. I have a few podcasts I keep up on (mostly sports in nature like Fantasy Focus Football &amp;amp; The BS Report). Music-wise, I used to have just a few of my favorite new albums stashed on my iPhone or put up with Spotify&amp;#39;s infernal ads. Recently though, I discovered the wonder that is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.subsonic.org/pages/index.jsp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Subsonic&lt;/a&gt;. It takes some networking know-how but I now have my entire music collection (all 200GB worth) available to me on my phone and my work PC. For free. It&amp;#39;s revolutionized my music-listening world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Besides your phone and computer, what gadget can&amp;#39;t you live without?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, my wife and I can&amp;#39;t live without the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foscam.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Foscam&lt;/a&gt; security camera that we set up as a baby monitor. I again used a little network trickery to set it up so that we can view it anywhere we&amp;#39;re at, either on our phones or the web. It&amp;#39;s been great for keeping an eye on Audrey and my wife loves it. It was an all together cheap solution compared to many of the over-priced baby monitor systems out there. We spent less than $100 for the camera and the apps for our phones/iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&amp;#39;s your sleep routine like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to get at least 6 hours a night. 7 is optimal. I&amp;#39;m usually in bed by 11:30 and up by 6am. I&amp;#39;m going to start experimenting with some of these &amp;quot;sleep cycle&amp;quot; alarm apps to see if they&amp;#39;re worth the hype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What everyday thing are you better at than anyone else?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m pretty good at creating efficient systems of getting things done and then sticking with that system. I&amp;#39;ll also continue to prove it out to make sure it&amp;#39;s the best solution possible. I do this with my daily commute. I&amp;#39;m constantly looking for the quickest way there and back. I&amp;#39;m never content to just stick with one route. There&amp;#39;s always got to be a faster way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&amp;#39;s the best advice you&amp;#39;ve ever received?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Energy creates energy. Potential is only realized when it becomes kinetic. It&amp;#39;s simple and it&amp;#39;s cyclical. I&amp;#39;m very momentum-driven and I sometimes struggle with initiation and getting things started, so this is huge for me. If I can just push past that initial opposing force of procrastination/laziness/whatever, then I can&amp;#39;t be stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything else you want to share with readers?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m a &lt;a href=&quot;/2008/03/28/im-a-serial-archivist.html&quot;&gt;serial archivist&lt;/a&gt;. I love archiving and organizing. For Christmas this year, my father-in-law got me a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getdoxie.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Doxie&lt;/a&gt; document scanner. Coupled with &lt;a href=&quot;http://evernote.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;#39;m using it to digitize my entire filing cabinet at some point in 2013. And I couldn&amp;#39;t be more excited about it. I have it all mapped out in Workflowy. And I&amp;#39;ll be getting to it right after I finish reorganizing my entire music collection (to better work with Subsonic) and then my entire media collection. Priorities, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 04:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2013/02/18/how-i-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2013/02/18/how-i-work.html</guid>
        
        <category>futures</category>
        
        <category>that-sad-and-holy-glow</category>
        
        <category>soul-driver</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How To Know You&#39;re From Kansas City</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;About nine years ago when I still lived in Ohio, two of my good friends at the time just so happened to be from Missouri and Kansas. It&amp;#39;s kind of a long story how they got there, but it could be said that they found a lot of our local idiosyncrasies hilarious. One day they decided to compile a  fairly smarting list of these quirky traits and emailed it to all of their Ohio friends for a good laugh (it was 2003, we emailed a lot back then). They wrote it all under the moniker &amp;quot;The MO-KAN Connection&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;a href=&quot;2005-08-22-108&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fairly smarting list&lt;/a&gt; --&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll admit, I didn&amp;#39;t take it as kindly then as I do looking back on it now. It was pretty darn funny. But sometimes it&amp;#39;s not very much fun to listen to someone with an outside perspective make jokes about &amp;quot;your town&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;your upbringing&amp;quot;. I was born and raised in T-County (Tuscarawas County for long, and yea they made fun of the name too), so sometimes I just didn&amp;#39;t know any different. It&amp;#39;s good every now and then to take a look at things from a different point of view (keep this in mind as you continue reading).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cuz now, the tables have turned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s nine years later, and I&amp;#39;ve been living in Kansas City for over two years. Both those friends of mine have moved back to the Greater Kansas City area as well, so it&amp;#39;s time for me to give my own little dose of perspective on their home city/state (one of them is actually from Springfield but many of these still apply). Now granted, KC may not be as quirky as Ohio Amish country, I&amp;#39;ll give you that. But you guys still do some pretty crazy stuff out here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here goes, make sure to read this knowing the love behind which it was crafted. Also, read it with humility. Cuz it&amp;#39;s all preeeeeeetty much true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;You know you&amp;#39;re from Kansas City if...&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You think KU vs. MU is one of the most storied rivalries in college sports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can&amp;#39;t wait to take out-of-town guests to see the spectacle that is The Plaza.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You call two slabs of meat on a plain piece of white bread with a dollop of BBQ sauce and a pickle on the side &amp;quot;good BBQ&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You think people from Johnson County can drive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You call a trip to the Ozarks &amp;quot;a vacation&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;#39;t think it&amp;#39;s weird that the &amp;quot;University of Kansas&amp;quot; and the &amp;quot;University of Missouri&amp;quot; are abbreviated KU &amp;amp; MU instead of UK &amp;amp; UM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;#39;t understand why the previous statement was included in this list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;#39;re considering moving from the suburbs to the city just so you&amp;#39;ll be assured of getting Google Fiber.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You actually enjoy the ketchup &amp;amp; mustard color scheme that the Chiefs have employed since that combination of colors actually looked good together back in nineteen-NEVER.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You really did think it was &amp;quot;Our Time&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You place the word &amp;quot;highway&amp;quot; after the road it is referring to instead of before like the rest of America, e.g. &amp;quot;71 highway&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;69 highway&amp;quot;, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;#39;ve never heard of a drive-thru liquor store.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You could lead someone right to Truman&amp;#39;s birthplace like the whole of your existence depends on you knowing this information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can name with astounding certainty which Kansas City news anchors are gay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You defy all pronunciation rules and logic by saying the word ornery (oRn-er-y) like this: &amp;quot;on-ree&amp;quot;. (Ohio friends: Yes, that&amp;#39;s really how they say it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Have you been to the Plaza yet? You&amp;#39;ve got to check out the Plaza.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You actually believe that you get better cell reception on your Sprint phone just because their world headquarters is in OP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You know the best times to avoid the lines at Oklahoma Joe&amp;#39;s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;#39;ve been mugged at least once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your car has been broken into at least once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your house has been broken into at least once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;#39;ve never questioned why such a ridiculously asinine statement like &amp;quot;Rock Chalk Jayhawk&amp;quot; is your school&amp;#39;s battle cry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You know what &amp;quot;The Triangle&amp;quot; is and when to avoid it at all costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You think that arguing with your buddies &amp;quot;which KC restaurant has the best BBQ in the city?&amp;quot; is a wise use of your time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You know exactly where The Goodfoot is playing tonight. Because it&amp;#39;s the exact same place they played at last week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will only fill up your car at a Quik Trip.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You give directions to your home by mentioning the nearest recognizable intersection, e.g. &amp;quot;95th &amp;amp; Metcalf&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;75th &amp;amp; Wornall&amp;quot;, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You consider the 6th inning sing-along to &amp;quot;Friends in Low Places&amp;quot; a fine Kauffman Stadium tradition, even though Garth Brooks isn&amp;#39;t from Kansas City and it JUST MAKES NO SENSE WHATSOEVER.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You think Lee&amp;#39;s Summit is just a short drive away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Seriously, you haven&amp;#39;t been to the Plaza? We need to take you to the Plaza.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You root for the Chiefs, the Cardinals and whichever NBA team your favorite KU player is currently on. And you can&amp;#39;t understand why anyone would ever want to root for all the pro sports teams from just ONE city.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You call anything north of the river the &amp;quot;Northland&amp;quot;. And you REFUSE to ever go there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;#39;re not-so-secretly proud that Missouri is now considered by many to be the Meth Capital of the World.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;#39;ve pronounced it &amp;quot;Missour-uh&amp;quot; at some point in your life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You didn&amp;#39;t know that Hyvee and PriceChopper weren&amp;#39;t nationally recognized grocery chains until you just read this sentence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You consider 90° to be a nice, breezy summer day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You regularly go on something you call &amp;quot;float trips&amp;quot; in the summer. These consist of a river, some form of flotation device and a massive amount of alcohol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your claim to fame is that you went to the same high school as Paul Rudd, Jason Sudeikis and that guy from Modern Family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You got a little bit too excited when Trader Joe&amp;#39;s opened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You actually root for the UMKC &amp;#39;Roos at whatever sporting events they compete in. No really though, what sporting events do they compete in?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You feel that &amp;quot;Schlitterbahn&amp;quot; is a great name for a water park.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You call moving to Johnson County &amp;quot;selling out&amp;quot;. But you do it anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You actually know someone who is sending their kids through the Kansas City school district.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The highlight of a Royals game for you is the tailgating you do beforehand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You think it&amp;#39;s normal to tailgate before a baseball game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You freak out about getting your hands on some Boulevard Chocolate Ale, even though you think it tastes like liquefied Hershey bars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Did you know Tech N9ne is from Kansas City?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Umm, who?&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You think the Chiefs are going to contend this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you go out of town you tell people the name of the suburb you&amp;#39;re from (instead of just saying you&amp;#39;re from &amp;quot;Kansas City&amp;quot;), as if they&amp;#39;ve ever heard of it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;#39;re not really offended by this list because you&amp;#39;ve found yourself agreeing with so much of it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With love,&lt;br&gt;
The T-County connection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find a copy of my buddies&amp;#39; list, &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;You Know You&amp;#39;re From T-County If...&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://bluestarmorning.xanga.com/11899865/item/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, on my old Xanga site. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 02:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2012/07/27/how-to-know-youre-from-kansas-city.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2012/07/27/how-to-know-youre-from-kansas-city.html</guid>
        
        <category>kc-accidental</category>
        
        <category>we-laugh-indoors</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On Leaving And Lebron</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s been a year now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One year ago last Wednesday, I packed up everything I could fit into a little, blue Mazda and headed west. It was one of the hardest things I&amp;#39;ll probably ever do in my life. Leaving my family, my friends and the only life I had known for the last 28 and half years wasn&amp;#39;t an easy call. But there I was, on July 6th, 2010, watching my parents fade away in my rearview as I set a course for the great unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or Kansas City, as the dot on my GPS map insisted on informing me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days later, you decided it was time to leave Ohio too. But with much bigger fanfare, naturally. Hours of news-cycle time, rampant speculation, and a much-hyped TV special were all dedicated to your big &amp;quot;Decision&amp;quot;. Most Ohioans weren&amp;#39;t too worried. I mean, how could you leave your &lt;em&gt;home&lt;/em&gt;? You were our &amp;quot;chosen one&amp;quot;, after all. You were the savior of Cleveland sports. The one to finally bring a championship to our hard-luck city. Fate had finally shone down upon us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was our time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We grew up with you. I, personally, saw you play three of your high school championship games at the state tournaments. I was never a particularly big basketball fan, but you had a way of igniting a passion for the game out of indifference. You turned arenas electric. We were all witnesses. And then, the impossible happened: the lowly Cavaliers lucked into taking you 1st in the draft. A once-in-a-generation talent &lt;em&gt;from our area&lt;/em&gt; coming back to &lt;em&gt;represent our area&lt;/em&gt; to the rest of the country? Northeast Ohio was abuzz. It was too good to be true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/news_poster-witness-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Quitness&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And boy, you sure knew how to put on a show. My dad bought season tickets to your games even though we lived an hour and a half away. My parents, especially, loved going to watch you play. You turned &lt;em&gt;my mom&lt;/em&gt; into a basketball fan. The games she actually let me go to with my dad will be remembered as some of the best sports experiences of my life. You turned 20,562 screaming fans into a close-knit community every night. There just wasn&amp;#39;t anything like it. With the game on the line, we looked to you. We knew you could &amp;quot;turn it on&amp;quot; whenever you wanted and take over the game. The rest of the team just stood and watched you work your magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/cavs-fam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cavs in my blood&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was, until, they started talking about New York. The playoff losses started mounting. The pressure on you to win now started growing. We expected you to stay, to keep fighting for your city. You &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fannation.com/truth_and_rumors/view/174990-lebrons-goal-bring-title-to-cleveland&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said it yourself&lt;/a&gt;, you weren&amp;#39;t going to stop until you brought home a championship to the city of Cleveland. Let ESPN talk all they want, we&amp;#39;d say, you wouldn&amp;#39;t &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; leave Ohio before you did, would you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, however, called it all along. You were going to leave. This &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; Cleveland we&amp;#39;re talking about, the most down-trodden sports city in the entire country. This is just the way things go here. In Ohio, we&amp;#39;re born defeatist. And because of it, nearly everyone in our generation is looking for a ticket out. Maybe you were just looking for your chance all along? The signs were there: the Yankees hats, your love for the Cowboys. I mean, really? You never wanted to make this your home, did you? We should have known better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first got the inkling to leave in the winter of 2009. I had just moved out on my own for the first time. My own apartment, all to myself. I was honestly just hoping to find some peace in living alone. It never came. Instead, I grew more introverted as my friends all got married or moved away. I was 27 with the specter of 30 fast approaching. The pressure was mounting to grow up fast: get married, buy a house, in whatever order you&amp;#39;d like. But I had exhausted all my options in Ohio. I was &lt;a href=&quot;/2010/7/5/choose-your-own-adventure.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;spinning my wheels&lt;/a&gt;. After a year of looking at possibilities: recording school in Florida, the always enticing idea of Californ-i-a, etc., I started working up the nerve it would take to actually move away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had always said I&amp;#39;d one day break free of the captive orbit that Ohio kept us all in. She&amp;#39;s an enchanter, though, and you need a darn fine reason for her to let you go. Luckily, mine drove to Ohio and met me at a youth rally I was leading praise at on New Year&amp;#39;s Day 2010. And she just so happened to be from Kansas City. One very option I had &lt;a href=&quot;/2010/7/5/choose-your-own-adventure.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;already been considering&lt;/a&gt;. She was my tipping point. It was then just a matter of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six months later, I was on the road to Kansas City with no job or place to stay ahead of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave my &amp;quot;decision&amp;quot; to my parents in their kitchen after one of my mom&amp;#39;s regular, delicious home-cooked meals. She fought back tears but said she understood. She wanted me to be happy and knew I wasn&amp;#39;t. I fought back tears when she asked if I&amp;#39;d ever consider moving back. I told my close friends in the same living room we usually talked about Jesus and drank beers. I told my niece on our back porch before she was old enough to understand what I was saying. I asked her to not forget about me when I&amp;#39;m gone. Those are memories I&amp;#39;ll always hold dear. Ones that I still can&amp;#39;t shake without crying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There weren&amp;#39;t any TV cameras, or captive audiences, or charities, or cheesy flannel shirts (well, maybe a few flannel shirts). I didn&amp;#39;t have the luxury of playing soft-toss with Jim Gray at some remote location in Greenwich, Connecticut (I mean, c&amp;#39;mon...New England?). No, there wasn&amp;#39;t a whole wide world of sports waiting to hear what I had decided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/lebron-decision.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dat flannel tho...&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at &lt;em&gt;least&lt;/em&gt; there was heartache. It broke my heart to leave Ohio. It broke my heart to feel like I was letting my family down by moving away. It broke my heart to know that I wouldn&amp;#39;t be living life beside these people anymore. That I wouldn&amp;#39;t be able to just drop by after work to talk and eat dinner with my parents. That I wouldn&amp;#39;t be going to Grandma&amp;#39;s after church on Sundays anymore. God had knit our hearts so close together for so many years and now our relationship would only exist on the other end of a telephone or computer screen. &lt;em&gt;That&lt;/em&gt; is heartbreaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it&amp;#39;s standard to write about all the favorite places that you&amp;#39;ll miss in your home state once you move away. But I don&amp;#39;t have a lot of &amp;quot;favorite places&amp;quot; in Ohio. I just have a lot of favorite &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt; in Ohio. And the times and places I&amp;#39;ll remember most are almost always tied to the people that I was able to share them with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know what else was heartbreaking? Watching your so-called &amp;quot;Decision&amp;quot; from the bar of a seafood restaurant on the outskirts of Kansas City. Feeling the hope of an entire region fade away on national television from 800 miles away is heartbreaking. I knew right then what the reaction would be. And I, for one, was glad I wasn&amp;#39;t in Ohio to see it first-hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Here we go again.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being out here for the aftermath has made me realize that no one outside of Ohio really gets it. It&amp;#39;s a situation that is so uniquely ours. I watched you play a preseason game here in KC while my emotions were still raw. A friend made me a sign. I wore all Cleveland garb, screamed my lungs out in derision, and embarrassed all my friends. I&amp;#39;m sure it was nothing like being in Cleveland for your first game back at The Q, but it sure was cathartic. &amp;quot;Get over it, free agents leave,&amp;quot; my new KC friends would say. No, not this one. It&amp;#39;s bigger than that. He&amp;#39;s supposed to understand. He&amp;#39;s one of &lt;em&gt;us&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or at least we &lt;em&gt;thought&lt;/em&gt; you were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/lebron-heated.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Heat check&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think Dan Wetzel of Yahoo Sports put the whole thing in &lt;a href=&quot;http://sports.yahoo.com/nba/news;_ylt=AoWfdJHNo5Q7zT3ZweCYfDW8vLYF?slug=dw-wetzel_cleveland_laughs_at_lebron_james_061211&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;perspective&lt;/a&gt; best:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No city has lost like this one, not a single major professional sports championship since 1964, when the Browns won a pre-Super Bowl NFL title. You’d have to be in your mid-50s to remember it. Cleveland’s modern sports memories are defined in short terms, as if elaborating is just too painful: The Drive, The Fumble, The Shot, The Move and, of course, The Decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want collapses? The 1997 World Series is as bad as anything the Cubs or Red Sox ever dealt with. It’s just this city doesn’t have the media poets to chronicle it like Chicago or Boston. You want the true gut punch? Their beloved Browns moved to Baltimore only to finally get their act together and win a Super Bowl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there was this, LeBron James, the local kid from Akron, the one who claimed he understood your heartache, the one you defended for years, the one that was finally going to deliver sporting glory. He bails for some fair-weather sports town and an arena full of white-covered chairs with pretty people who can’t even be bothered to watch the game while it’s going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did it break your heart to leave Ohio? I know it didn&amp;#39;t break your heart to leave Cleveland. The way you left tells us that much. Your big Lithuanian friend &lt;em&gt;who didn&amp;#39;t even grow up in America&lt;/em&gt;, let alone Cleveland, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.waitingfornextyear.com/2010/08/zydrunas-ilgauskas-thanks-fans-in-sunday-morning-ad/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;showed everyone&lt;/a&gt; how you leave a beloved city with class: &amp;quot;I...hope you realize that Cleveland will always be home to me.&amp;quot; You&amp;#39;d do well to take notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is, we glossed over your arrogance. The showboating, the posturing, the egotism, the chalk toss. It was downplayed because you were a &amp;quot;hometown&amp;quot; boy. We saw it and just laughed it off. And that&amp;#39;s on us. But now, it&amp;#39;s on you. We&amp;#39;ve grieved, but we&amp;#39;re &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P3pbLyHCOCo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;moving on&lt;/a&gt;. Akron might take you back, but Ohio never will. You&amp;#39;ve taken your place in the long list of dark spots in Cleveland&amp;#39;s sports history. Did you really envision it turning out any differently? If you really were ashamed of claiming Ohio as your home, you wouldn&amp;#39;t have to worry about it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ohio is ashamed of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s been a year and I think I&amp;#39;ve finally come to terms with leaving Ohio. I might&amp;#39;ve just come to terms with you leaving too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t blame you for wanting to leave Ohio. I mean, look at me, I left too. No, I blame you for the way you left. And that&amp;#39;s coming from a guy who tried his best to leave the right way. I gave my job a two-month notice. I got my affairs in order. I wanted to give people time to adjust. But really, I think I was the one who needed the adjustment time. It was a transition. I needed time to grieve and let people grieve. You don&amp;#39;t just pull the rug out from under people&amp;#39;s feet. Not when the particular people you&amp;#39;re hoodwinking have had such a sorry history of similar close-calls and let-downs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve built up so many defense mechanisms over the years as Ohioans, ones that you seemed to have deliberately played into. We have it in our blood to be confidently optimistic and then curse the wind when the same thing happens &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cleveland_Browns_relocation_controversy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;over&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1997_World_Series&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;over&lt;/a&gt; again. We build up just enough hope so that there&amp;#39;s a substantial enough amount to get dashed away later. Sarcasm has become engrained in our way of life. We&amp;#39;re cocky to the Steelers fans, to the Celtics fans, to the Yankees &amp;amp; Red Sox fans and then just fall back to &amp;quot;Well, there&amp;#39;s always next year!&amp;quot; when the cycle continues. Whole &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.waitingfornextyear.com/2011/07/hurry-up-wait-and-be-patient-with-browns/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;websites&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.clevelandfrowns.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;internet followings&lt;/a&gt; have grown out of this effort in futility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe me, I wanted to leave all that negativity behind too. But leaving has given me a new love for my home state. It&amp;#39;s that fond love that grows with distance. And I bet it&amp;#39;s growing in you now too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirteen hours on the road by yourself gives you just enough time to get excited about what you&amp;#39;re doing, then doubt what you&amp;#39;re doing, and then get excited all over again. My mood swings on that never-ending drive through the Plains were most likely dictated by the ups and downs of the wide array of music I had put into playlists for the long journey out. Luckily, it kept me distracted just long enough from thinking about how I honestly didn&amp;#39;t know where I would be staying when I got out to Kansas City. I just knew that it&amp;#39;s where I needed to be. A few rather kind folks decided to take me in. I stayed on my best friend&amp;#39;s couch for a night. And then transferred my meager belongings into the den of a house that belonged to three guys I barely knew. They graciously allowed me to stay there until I landed a job in my new home city. That stay would last for just under three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#39;t know it then, but I had just happened into one of the most amazing group of friends that I&amp;#39;ve ever been apart of. Yes, I had to make the heart-rending decision to leave my family and friends back in Ohio. But I met, dated, and am going to marry the girl of my dreams out here in KC in three months. She wound up being a pretty good reason to leave Ohio. The price was steep, but I&amp;#39;d say it was a fairly even trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, can you say the same thing? Was it worth it? I&amp;#39;ll be honest, I rooted for you to lose. And just about all of Ohio was darn happy when you did. Even if you would have pulled out some late-game magic like you always seemed to do for us, would it have been as fulfilling? Wouldn&amp;#39;t it have been &lt;em&gt;that much sweeter&lt;/em&gt; if you were winning it all for Cleveland? Wouldn&amp;#39;t that be a much greater cause? It sure looks like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/07/11/lebron-james-popularity-all-time-low_n_894819.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rest of America&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://sports.espn.go.com/nba/news/story?id=5575810&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;thinks so&lt;/a&gt;. But hey, you made your choice. And I made mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it turned out to be the best one I&amp;#39;ve ever made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“All the people that was rooting on me to fail, at the end of the day they have to wake up tomorrow and have the same life that they had before they woke up today,” James said. “They have the same personal problems they had today. I’m going to continue to live the way I want to live and continue to do the things that I want to do with me and my family and be happy with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They can get a few days or a few months or whatever the case may be on being happy about not only myself, but the Miami Heat not accomplishing their goal. But they have to get back to the real world at some point.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, now &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; have to get back to the real world. We already live here. The real world of making a decision and having to stick with it. There&amp;#39;s no turning back. It&amp;#39;s I-70 westbound straight into the setting sun with only pictures of your family and the hope of what lies on the other side to keep you going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But whatever you have to say to help you sleep at night. You&amp;#39;ve made your bed. You chose and you lost. But hey, coming from Ohio you should be pretty familiar with that empty feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, well, there&amp;#39;s always next year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 03:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2011/07/12/on-leaving-and-lebron.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2011/07/12/on-leaving-and-lebron.html</guid>
        
        <category>bloodbuzz-ohio</category>
        
        <category>fambly</category>
        
        <category>all-is-a-game</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Facebook Is The Mark Of The Beast</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I mean, is there really any doubt?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know one thing, I used to write things on the internet. Sometimes they were interesting, sometimes they were complete drivel. But the key was, I wrote them. I sat down at my computer, I opened a blog post window and I wrote.
These days, I&amp;#39;m more likely to open a rapid succession of Facebook and Twitter windows and read things other people have written. Some of them interesting, some complete drivel. I still write, but it&amp;#39;s more fragments and pieces of thoughts than what I would have otherwise have formed into complete phrases within a blog post a few years back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each tweet, each status update have given me a sense of completion, but they&amp;#39;re just a taste. They&amp;#39;re nothing like that thrill of hitting the &amp;quot;publish&amp;quot; button on a long-form work that you&amp;#39;ve given serious thought and contemplation to. I&amp;#39;m sure it&amp;#39;s somewhere near what a novelist feels when they hit the return key at the end of a completed chapter. It&amp;#39;s that sense of fear in knowing your thoughts will be read, but also, that satisfaction in knowing you&amp;#39;ve created something and you&amp;#39;ve put yourself out there to be critiqued. And well, that counts for something, doesn&amp;#39;t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this is a post about how I haven&amp;#39;t posted. And my struggle to figure out why. I&amp;#39;ve had an idea of something to write for going on a year now. And I just haven&amp;#39;t written it. This would have bothered me a few years ago. Back then, I &lt;a href=&quot;/tag/xanga&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wrote something&lt;/a&gt; just about every day. It was more of a journal of my day&amp;#39;s events than anything. But I took great care to fashion each post. I designed the site with great attention to detail. I took a lot of pride in my silly, little Xanga page. And now I laugh a lot when I go back and read through it. But the point is, it&amp;#39;s still there. You can still go and read all the thoughts, emotions and events of my life for the span of well over three years. It&amp;#39;s riveting material, let me forewarn you. Wikipedia rabbit-trails have nothing on my Xanga site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also a post about how I&amp;#39;m not quitting Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I&amp;#39;ve read blog posts about this sort of phenomena before. And usually all of them end with the author resigning himself to quitting Facebook/Twitter and only posting on their blogs from here on out. That&amp;#39;s great and all, except for the mere fact that no one will read anything you&amp;#39;ll write from here on out. There are a few exceptions, but on the whole everyone looks to Facebook to see what&amp;#39;s going on in their world. Facebook (and Twitter to a lesser extent) has become the only online social hub. We&amp;#39;ve all taken it&amp;#39;s mark. There is no socializing outside it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s a bit drastic, I know. But it&amp;#39;s the future, and I&amp;#39;ve accepted that. It grieves me a little that sites like Xanga aren&amp;#39;t the social epicenter anymore. But I get why they died, they weren&amp;#39;t instant enough. They had a lazy pace to them. But I think it was that lazy pace that made it easier for deliberate thinkers like me to keep stride with our quicker-witted online peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet is just getting so fast. And I can&amp;#39;t keep up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I log on, read about everyone else&amp;#39;s day, maybe type a few words and then close up shop. When I had my Xanga, life was the only thing that kept me from updating it. These days, it&amp;#39;s the internet that keeps me from updating about my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose I could just resolve myself to write more. And I&amp;#39;m going to do my best (starting with that post I&amp;#39;ve been thinking up for about a year). After all, my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birkman.com/birkmanMethod/whatIsTheBirkmanMethod.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Birkman report&lt;/a&gt; told me that, above all, I&amp;#39;m a &amp;quot;Literary&amp;quot;-type, and that I&amp;#39;m not completely fulfilled unless I&amp;#39;m consistently writing or doing something close to it. The fact remains, though: the internet has changed. And so too, must my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to anyone who has stuck around to read my infrequent writings on this site, I certainly appreciate your patience. I truly hope to get to a post of more substance shortly (it&amp;#39;s relevancy window is closing rapidly).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then...completion is just a click away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. - In this same online writing vein, a few friends and I have started an online newspaper detailing the insignificant minutiae of our daily lives. It&amp;#39;s more for us than you but it&amp;#39;s a good time regardless. It&amp;#39;s called &amp;quot;The 6th Degree&amp;quot;, and you can check it out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.the-6th-degree.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This was originally posted on an old Squarespace blog of mine. Most of the references, links and jokes are probably dead.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 02:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2011/07/06/facebook-is-the-mark-of-the-beast.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2011/07/06/facebook-is-the-mark-of-the-beast.html</guid>
        
        <category>that-sad-and-holy-glow</category>
        
        <category>wolf-am-i</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top 10 Of &#39;10</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s been a while since I&amp;#39;ve posted a year-end best of list. This is due mostly to the fact that I haven&amp;#39;t listened to 10 albums in a year that I liked enough to put in a year-end best of list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, thankfully, I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tops:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Violet (The National) -&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;#39;m consistently blown away by the stuff these guys are coming up with record after record. They&amp;#39;re just consistently great. And that&amp;#39;s no easy task (re: Midlake, below). &amp;quot;Boxer&amp;quot; was phenomenal and somehow they were able to top themselves again. They also recorded my new favorite &amp;quot;Ohio&amp;quot; song. I&amp;#39;m sure they&amp;#39;ll be pleased to know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Age of Adz/All Delighted People EP (Sufjan Stevens) -&lt;/strong&gt; It wouldn&amp;#39;t be a best-of list by Ryan Straits without an appearance by Sufjan. I&amp;#39;ll be honest, it took me a while to get into both of these records (I packaged them together because they came out so close to each other), but once I did I couldn&amp;#39;t get enough. It also helped that I saw him perform these live soon after the albums released. Epic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Promise (Bruce Springsteen) -&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;quot;Darkness on the Edge of Town&amp;quot; is probably my favorite Boss album, so an album of B-Sides recorded during the &amp;quot;Darkness&amp;quot; sessions is naturally going to be right up my alley. And the Boss DOES NOT disappoint. The revamped version of &amp;quot;Racing In the Street&amp;quot; is worth the Deluxe Box set price, alone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go (Jonsi) -&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;#39;s Sigur Ros on speed. And really, they were in need of a lil pep-up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brothers (The Black Keys) -&lt;/strong&gt; In retrospect, I should have been a bigger fan of a band that hails from Akron, Ohio. Spoiler alert: I am now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shame, Shame (Dr. Dog) -&lt;/strong&gt; Not as great of an album as their past two releases but I&amp;#39;ll take sub-standard Dr. Dog any day over your best Justin Bieber. Srsly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Suburbs (Arcade Fire) -&lt;/strong&gt; The first 3 songs? AWESOME. The rest? Ehhh. Doesn&amp;#39;t have the re-playability that &amp;quot;Funeral&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Neon Bible&amp;quot; had. However, I would listen to &amp;quot;Rococo&amp;quot; over and over if it meant I got to see these guys live sometime this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walking On A Dream (Empire of the Sun) -&lt;/strong&gt; They&amp;#39;re fun, and different, and great to workout to. See, it really doesn&amp;#39;t take much to crack my top 10.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infinite Arms (Band of Horses) -&lt;/strong&gt; Nice &amp;#39;n easy listening. That&amp;#39;s pretty much it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saint Bartlett (Damien Jurado) -&lt;/strong&gt; Sadly, I was never as into ol&amp;#39; Damien as much my buddy Dave was growing up. However, I&amp;#39;m into this new record. Maybe now I&amp;#39;ll go back and re-listen to some of those older albums Dave kept yapping about. Maybe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friends:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tadaima (The Non) -&lt;/strong&gt; I had the chance to see these guys twice over the summer while I was mobile and unemployed. There&amp;#39;s really no comparison for their live show. Seriously, a must-see.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wanderer, O Wanderer EP (Come Wind) -&lt;/strong&gt; Come Wind is comprised of some very dear friends of mine. I knew they were good, but I didn&amp;#39;t know they were THIS good. I&amp;#39;d be lying if I said this album didn&amp;#39;t stay in my car stereo for quite a few weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holy Spirits EP (State Bird) -&lt;/strong&gt; They seem to reinvent themselves with every new record. Every time I think I&amp;#39;m not gonna like the new sound. And every time I&amp;#39;m proven wrong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Badlands (Chris Staples)/Future Paths (Discover America) -&lt;/strong&gt; I now live in the same city that Chris &amp;amp; I got robbed at gunpoint together in. I cry nightly in the shower; he keeps putting out solid records. (Editors note: Chris Staples = Discover America)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Honorable Mention:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Invented (Jimmy Eat World) -&lt;/strong&gt; They seem to be hearkening back a few albums with this latest release. I had written them off but if their next album continues in this trend I might need to write them back on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I Had A Hi-Fi (Nada Surf) -&lt;/strong&gt; I pretty much like most anything these guys come out with (all the way back to &amp;quot;Popular&amp;quot;). I felt a little hoodwinked, though, when I found out (after several listens) that this was just a covers album. Originals &amp;gt; covers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mines (Menomena) -&lt;/strong&gt; Before this album I could point to one Menomena song that I liked. Now I can point to a whole album.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Beautiful Dark Twisted Fantasy (Kanye West) -&lt;/strong&gt; My quasi-secret Kanye fandom continues. He may be an idiot, but he&amp;#39;s got more talent in his pinkie finger than Taylor Swift has in...well, you get the idea.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most Disappointing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Courage of Others (Midlake) -&lt;/strong&gt; I really, really, REALLY wanted to like this album. But I expected a heckuva lot more from a band that forces us to wait 4 years between releases. I&amp;#39;d rather just listen to &amp;quot;Head Home&amp;quot; on repeat until they release their next one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forgiveness Rock Record (Broken Social Scene) -&lt;/strong&gt; The sum used to be greater than it&amp;#39;s parts. Now its struggling to get all it&amp;#39;s parts back just to record a new album. They&amp;#39;re officially too big for their britches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Chorus Of Storytellers (The Album Leaf) -&lt;/strong&gt; Once upon a time, The Album Leaf were the only ones that sounded like The Album Leaf. Now, everyone does. Time for a reinvention, Mr. LaValle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Congratulations (MGMT) -&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;quot;What the #$%&amp;amp; is this?&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoyed! A new entry coming soon-ish...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This was originally posted on an old Squarespace blog of mine. Most of the references, links and jokes are probably dead.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2010 23:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2010/12/29/top-10-of-10.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2010/12/29/top-10-of-10.html</guid>
        
        <category>dad-rock</category>
        
        <category>exit-music-for-a-film</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
