<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ghost States</title>
    <description>&lt;i&gt;The art of the in-between&lt;/i&gt;
</description>
    <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.ryanstraits.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 22:19:50 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 22:19:50 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Intro: The Middle Chapters</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Midlife is what happens after the credits roll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how you slice it, midlife is just a uniquely and profoundly unremarkable period of life. By it’s very definition, it is an age &lt;em&gt;between&lt;/em&gt; other ages. It’s interstitial, domestic, and unexceptional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this is mostly because middle age is a stage of life that is, by-and-large, bereft of any major milestones. Compare that with your teens and twenties, society grants those age ranges so many baked-in rites of passage. Every year there’s something new:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Driving!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Graduating!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Voting!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drinking!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Career[ing]!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marrying!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Birthing!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More drinking!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, what’s next? Realistically, a whole lot of nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Midlife feels like it could seemingly go on forever. It is “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/2016/03/17/469822644/8-ways-you-can-survive-and-thrive-in-midlife&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a book without any structure, sentences, periods, commas, paragraphs, chapters…or punctuation&lt;/a&gt;.” And so, without any of these built-in cultural chapters, you can quickly find yourself slipping into one fantastically dreadful existential breakdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might even call it: a midlife crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first started writing on my experiences growing up and getting older soon after my 33rd birthday. Life was speeding by so fast up to that point that it was honestly the first time I recall thinking to myself, “Y’know, I’m kind of starting to get old.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your thirties are that tweener age range that, as a kid, you can remember your parents being, but never dedicated much forethought to reaching yourself. When you’re young, it’s just some far-off dot on the horizon. That boring mid-point between “younger” and “older”. It’s Marty McFly watching his dorky-dad-self in the &lt;em&gt;way distant&lt;/em&gt; future of 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t say what it was specifically about turning 33 that tripped a breaker in me the way it did. Maybe it was realizing that I had officially reached “the age of the Lord”. You know, the age when Jesus decided he’d had enough of his human existence and kicked it into high-gear back to heaven. (He had to know what he was doing, right?) Maybe it was the realization that virtually every pro athlete essentially reaches the washed-up phase of their careers around age 33 (the one exception being &lt;a href=&quot;/2011/07/12/on-leaving-and-lebron.html&quot;&gt;LeBron&lt;/a&gt;, of course).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe it was that little bit of extra hurt I started to feel in my knees the day after I ran at the gym. Or the slight twinge of anxiety that shot through my gut when I realized how quickly my children were growing. Or the expanding list of doubts about beliefs I was so certain of all those years before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The best part of middle age is finding the perfect balance between anxiety about the future and regret about the past.&lt;/p&gt;— Chris Jones (@MySecondEmpire) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MySecondEmpire/status/563048116417728513&quot;&gt;February 4, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s because your 33rd year is right about when the full weight of “getting old” starts to set in. You’re starting to get a better picture of the frailty of your own body and the brevity of your own life. It’s roughly the age when you realize that if you’re not doing what you want with your life by this point, then maybe it’s time to start re-thinking your priorities. And if you’re not who you want to be by now, it’s likely time for a full-on sea change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be a bit disorienting, yes. But I’m learning that this is not a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, now that I’m smack dab in the middle of my thirties, I have come to recognize just how &lt;em&gt;crucial&lt;/em&gt; this time of life is. The middle is where the work happens. This is the proverbial “nose to the grindstone” portion of your life. It’s where things get &lt;em&gt;done&lt;/em&gt;. It’s where you become:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A better driver&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An &lt;em&gt;informed&lt;/em&gt; voter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A working professional&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A seasoned partner&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A mature parent&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A craft beer drinker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Midlife may not be filled with many “firsts”, but it will almost certainly be filled with many of your life’s “bests”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may not be able to see it quite yet, so let me report back on my early findings from where I sit at this stage of the game: your midlife crisis is a &lt;em&gt;gift&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your thirties are this sweet spot in the center and thick of it all. You’ve lived enough life to know what &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to do, while still possessing the agency over yourself and your choices to be able to do what you &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to do. Yes, midlife can be unremarkable. But it’s also this rare presentation of a second chance that we are afforded allowing us to regroup, refresh, re-purpose, and redirect. Getting a handle on your fragility may just be the wake-up call you need to remind yourself that you’re still in this thing. And you’ve got a long way left to go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/fabrizio-verrecchia-438342-unsplash-small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, I’ve resolved that if there are no inherent dividers in this section of the book, then I am just going to have to create them &lt;em&gt;myself&lt;/em&gt;. If society isn’t going to hand me any punctuation during these interminable middle years, then dammit, I am going to add my &lt;em&gt;own&lt;/em&gt; exclamation points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just like my expanding waistline can attest, there is a lot to love in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of waistlines, next up we’ll look at what growing up into a midlife body looks like. I promise, it’s not all bad!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;images-not-from-my-personal-camera-roll-are-provided-by-unsplash&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Images not from my personal camera roll are provided by&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unsplash&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2018/04/07/intro-the-middle-chapters.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2018/04/07/intro-the-middle-chapters.html</guid>
        
        <category>now-that-im-older</category>
        
        <category>a-midlife-guide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Midlife Guide To Growing Up</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I really thought I’d feel grown up by now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, aren’t your thirties when you’re supposed to have life figured out? And if not figured out, than at least well on your way.  Or I guess that’s what I had always assumed. In my younger years, if I ever looked ahead to life as a middle-aged man, I could only envision that future version of myself as someone who thoroughly had it all together. A married man? Yes. A family man? Sure. A career man? Naturally. And of course, the wisdom that would accompany each new phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, as I have discovered, is not actually how life works. Just because you’re getting older in age, doesn’t necessarily mean you’re “growing up”. Wisdom isn’t just knowing more than you used to. It’s having the humility to acknowledge that the older you get, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ryanstraits/status/970835905974960128&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;less you truly know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because the tree adds another ring, doesn’t mean it’s grown any closer to the sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gabriel-jimenez-150063-small-edit.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I started to think about what it looks like to &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; grow up. To grow upwards while &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; growing outwards. To grow taller while also growing &lt;em&gt;deeper&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The in’s and out’s of everyday life in your thirties don’t make it easy for many extended periods of introspection. However, once you open up that door, it’s near impossible to close. Never have I had such a simultaneous flood of answers, epiphanies, and transformational self discoveries flying at me all at once. And because there must always be balance in the force, those answers inevitably come laced with their own new set of deeper, harder, and more existential questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I felt like I needed to start writing a few things down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally, I had hoped to just post these musings in three simple blog posts touching on the themes of getting older and growing up. But all of the sudden, here I am three-plus years later with a likely &lt;em&gt;ten-part series&lt;/em&gt; on my hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m calling what follows a “guide” not because it is in any way definitive; I can only speak to the parts that the soles of my shoes have touched so far. I’m by no means attempting to claim any expertise on midlife as a whole. I’m writing this more as a compendium for myself: to remember back to what life was like during this time period and to also challenge myself for the journey ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s part memoir, part advice column, part commentary, part confessional, and part gag reel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/paper-beard-13807-300px.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt;, I know. However, I am hopeful that by releasing this thing one small chunk at a time it might promote some thought, perusal, or even a little discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you won’t find yourself relating with much or any of this at all, and that’s fine! There isn’t anything fantastical or hyperbolic here. Just the middle aged tales of a middle class dude from Middle America. I’m essentially the average of all things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the reason I wanted to write these thoughts in blog form, is so that If you ever happen to find yourself lost somewhere down the road, let these posts be a reminder that there are plenty of others out here treading a similar path. Plenty of thirty-somethings also trying to get a hold on their mortality and significance. Plenty of young parents feeling stuck in a neverending grind of messy diapers and messy finances. Plenty of once-believers wondering where the simple and &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt; faith of their youth ran off to. If my hemming, hawing, and fumbling through this stage of life can save somebody just a few clicks back of me a little pain and disappointment, then I suppose I’m fulfilling at least one of my duties as a &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt; grown up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because in the end, we’re all just growing up together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Friendship is born at that moment when one person says to another: “What! You too? I thought I was the only one.” - C.S. Lewis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2014-10-11 11.17.58-small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;My wife in Colorado, 2014&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a rough road-map of where we’ll be going over the next few weeks and months. I’ll come back and update here as a new chapter is released. Thanks for coming along for the ride!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2018/04/08/intro-the-middle-chapters.html&quot;&gt;Intro: The Middle Chapters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Part 1: A Grown-Up Body…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Part 2: Middling Age&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Part 3: A Grown-Up Soul…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Part 4: Life In The Future&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Part 5: Forever Summer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Part 6: The Dad Mule&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Part 7: A Grown-Up Spirit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Part 8: …&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Part 9: …&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Part 10: …&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. - If you’re new to me or my blog, the &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot; title=&quot;About Me!&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; page might be a great place to get yourself up to speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;images-not-from-my-personal-camera-roll-are-provided-by-unsplash&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Images not from my personal camera roll are provided by&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unsplash&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/featured/2018/04/06/a-midlife-guide-to-growing-up.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/featured/2018/04/06/a-midlife-guide-to-growing-up.html</guid>
        
        <category>now-that-im-older</category>
        
        <category>a-midlife-guide</category>
        
        
        <category>featured</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Grey Christmas</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I prefer winter and Fall, when you feel the bone structure of the landscape — the loneliness of it, the dead feeling of winter. Something waits beneath it, the whole story doesn’t show.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;~Andrew Wyeth &lt;!-- break --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, the majority of us are well aware that our Lord Jesus Christ’s birthday was not actually December 25th. And yet, that is where tradition continues to plant the western world’s most illustrious holiday. (Due to, you know, solstices and things of this nature.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those of us in flyover states, and generally anywhere but Florida and California, are also quite aware that weather-wise December is not the cheeriest month of the calendar year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, it’s often the bleakest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so we dream of White Christmases, because we know that if it’s not white and fluffy outside, it will most likely be grey and depressing. Without the spectacle that is the Christmas holiday season taking up most of our attention — and with seasonal affective disorder in full swing, December would be an undeniable downer of a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this about Christmas. I love that it’s plumb smack in the middle of the drabbest month of the year. It’s not quite orange and Indian Summer-y like the months preceding it, and it’s not yet cold and crystalline like the upcoming dead of winter. It’s literally half-autumn and half-winter. It’s muddy, stark and matted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point I could draw a parallel between the eponymous holiday and the act of the Son of God himself coming down into our grey, dreary existence and bringing pure, white heaven to earth some 2,000 years ago. But that analogy has been made time and again already. So I’m going to hang back on the dreariness for just a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a day-before-Christmas kind of guy. I love the build-up to the actual day-of. The anticipation and the mystery of the season. I love the wonder. There’s this palpable quality to it that we try to put into words, but just can’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like in all our gloomy Christmas songs. What other joyous holiday do you know of that has so many songs written about it in minor keys? I made a mixtape/CD/playlist of some of my favorites a few years back and it’s become the highlight of my annual Christmas music experience, when I actually let myself listen to Christmas music, that is (usually after December 1st, plus or minus a week).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of Sufjan on there, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ryanstraits/the-50-states-of-grief-b8c798f3ca87#.ksr5eiapi&quot;&gt;naturally&lt;/a&gt;, but there’s also a few renditions that some friends have recorded. And it perfectly captures the greyest qualities of Christmas that I enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up in Ohio also helped bake plenty of dreariness in to the holiday for me. Grey is practically Ohio’s state color (along with scarlet, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.osu.edu/&quot;&gt;of course&lt;/a&gt;). My wife makes fun of me, but when we go home to visit over Christmas, I like to just drive around a while and take it all in. I miss the inherent malaise. It’s nostalgic and melancholic all at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then we finally arrive at the day of Christmas itself, which comes first bright and gleaming. But then it slowly cedes back to grey as well. The anticipation soon follows. The tree is laid bare, the gifts are opened, and everyone’s back to their phones. The wonder is gone, the mystery is over, and the doldrums set back in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last 10–15 years or so, some good old friends — who have mostly all left our small Ohio home towns — reconvene back in the creaky apartment above the garage that used to be our regular hangout. We call it our Post-Holiday Blah’s Party. We catch up on weddings, children, and divorces. We reminisce. And we do our damnedest to fight off those blah’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s one more soiree to keep us going. One more festivity to look forward to. One more thing to keep our minds off the mid-winter dreck we’re about to re-enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s something glorious about this time of year that we all seem to nod and acknowledge in one way or another. The giving, the magic, the love shared amongst next of kin. The calm. There’s some great joy that’s waiting to burst forth in this season of dearth. It’s trapped and we’re doing our best to claw at it and prod it out into the light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see just enough of it every year that it keeps us merry. Festive. Full of hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it only comes in hints and whispers. And so we strive. And wonder. And keep the mystery alive for another season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And all within this beautifully miserable shade of grey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;this-post-was-originally-published-here&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was originally published&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ryanstraits/a-grey-christmas-81ffa7aa7467&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 08:56:56 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2015/12/19/a-grey-christmas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2015/12/19/a-grey-christmas.html</guid>
        
        <category>soul-driver</category>
        
        <category>fambly</category>
        
        <category>that-sad-and-holy-glow</category>
        
        <category>medium</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 50 States of Grief Project</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;sufjan-stevens-deep-dive-into-death-on-carrie-lowell-&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sufjan Stevens’ deep dive into death on “Carrie &amp;amp; Lowell”. &lt;!-- break --&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; I’m an unabashed Sufjan super-fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know there were many of us out there hoping this latest effort, out March 31, 2015 on Asthmatic Kitty Records, was a return to Sufjan’s early 2000’s form. While there is plenty of banjo strummin’ to keep the purists from tuning out, &lt;em&gt;Carrie &amp;amp; Lowell&lt;/em&gt; marks a fairly significant departure from the folk innocence we’ve all come to know and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly not more so than 2010’s techno-glitch-heavy &lt;em&gt;Age of Adz&lt;/em&gt;, mind you, but that record at least had plenty of Sufjan’s trademark lightheartedness spaced evenly between it’s drabber moments. “Too Much” and “Get Real, Get Right” were good examples, even if he tried to drown that eagerness out with beeps and zooms in minor keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I heard the first sampling of this new album, I don’t think I was alone in secretly praying that the textbook Sufjan youthful exuberance was back after a brief, trippy, digital detour. The kind of exuberance that was once accompanied by lilting orchestrations that rose to climactic explosions of flute, cymbals and spiritual exclamations. Orchestrations that fit perfectly with innocent, carefree lyrics that seemed to masterfully describe this undisturbed, uncomplicated life that we all wanted to exist somewhere. Lyrics that evoked idyllic images of young unrequited love, effortless faith, and child-like hope for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put simply, &lt;em&gt;Carrie &amp;amp; Lowell&lt;/em&gt; lays these notions to rest. This is Sufjan grown up and stripped bare. Those of us who were lobbying for a record full of “The Dress Looks Nice On You” sound-a-likes might be a tad disappointed to find out it’s a lot more “John Wayne Gacy” in nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not much of an exaggeration to say that this album is very literally just Sufjan and his banjo. It took me a few listens through to realize that there really isn’t a lick of percussion anywhere to be found. No wind instruments. No grand orchestrations. Instead, reverberated vocals, ethereal pads and spacey guitars do their best to fill the gaping sonic void.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Sufjan is fairly secretive about his recording process, I like to imagine that he took a Johnny Cash &lt;em&gt;American Recordings&lt;/em&gt; approach with &lt;em&gt;Carrie &amp;amp; Lowell&lt;/em&gt;. Wherein, he sat down with banjo in hand and sang and played his way through each song while Rick Rubin came along later, layering in just enough complexity behind Suf to get the song’s point across. Except maybe instead of Rick Rubin it was Sufjan’s buddies in The National doing the dirty work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lyrical fare hovers nearly entirely around the death of Sufjan’s mother, the eponymous Carrie, who passed away last year. The tension of their relationship (she left their family when Sufjan was very young) and the confusion he feels after her death are both themes that are layered on thick throughout the record. That dynamic, while it lends itself to some very rich songwriting, left me struggling to connect emotionally as I have yet to deal with such grief in my own life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The honesty that flows out of each one of these new batch of songs, however, is very palatable. Probably more so than any Sufjan record yet, I’ll give it that. The subject matter obviously lends itself to this. &lt;em&gt;Carrie &amp;amp; Lowell&lt;/em&gt; is a son coming to grips with the pain of a parent’s death and attempting to file away the pain that was caused &lt;em&gt;by&lt;/em&gt; that parent’s reckless life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a week of regular listening, “Fourth of July” is oddly the song that has stuck with me most. I think it’s because it’s the most un-Sufjan-like song he’s released to date. Rather than layered wispy vocals declaring the coming of the Lord, it plays as an intimate conversation between he and his dying mother and culminates with his naked voice numbly deadpanning “We’re all going to die…” throughout the final few refrains. It marks the thematic climax of the record and also it’s most downward-looking point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not all death and depression, though. “Should’ve Known Better” starts slowly but ends up just about as joyous as I would suppose a grieving man could muster. This apex arrives as Sufjan encourages himself “don’t back down…nothing can be changed” and beams over his brother’s daughter and “the beauty that she brings”. A few rays of sunlight do wind up breaking through after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, frankly, is not the Sufjan album that I wanted. But maybe, just maybe, it’s the one I needed. A pared back, mature record that speaks honestly and directly with little-to-no frills. I guess that’s what I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be wanting, anyways. Much like Sufjan, it’s probably time for super-fans like myself to stop pining for the past and grow up a little bit ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s all just hope that it isn’t another five years until we have new Sufjan Stevens material to keep pushing us along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;this-post-was-originally-publishedhere&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was originally published&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ryanstraits/the-50-states-of-grief-b8c798f3ca87&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 09:13:16 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2015/03/19/the-50-states-of-grief-project.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2015/03/19/the-50-states-of-grief-project.html</guid>
        
        <category>dad-rock</category>
        
        <category>now-that-im-older</category>
        
        <category>medium</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hate Before Love</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have this quirk. I tend to hate things that I wind up falling in love with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It happens a lot with new apps. I think an idea is stupid and write it off, then it comes back around to woo me. Twitter is one example. I &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ryanstraits/statuses/789269312&quot; title=&quot;First Tweet&quot;&gt;signed up in 2008&lt;/a&gt;, but didn’t start using it until 2010. Now it’s the first app I go to on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s happened even more often with music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back around 2000, a good friend wanted me to download &amp;amp; burn him a copy of this new British band he had just heard of. For some reason, I instantly couldn’t stand them. Something about their sound irked me, like they were just sampling The Bends era Radiohead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years later, I heard “In My Place” on a TV show and had to know what band it was. Well, it was obviously Coldplay. I had missed the boat, they were pretty good. After that, I couldn’t get enough. And then I had to get caught up on Parachutes, which everyone was sick of back in 2000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there was Springsteen. I didn’t have any friends into The Boss, I just hated him on mostly political grounds. I was a fairly heavy conservative back around 2004 and he was prominent in the Democratic opposition to The Iraq War and George W. Bush. Something about his political activism struck me the wrong way, so I wrote him and his American-blue-collar-rock off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to the spring of 2008. I had just started course-correcting myself back to being a moderate. I was beginning to think towards voting for Barack Obama. But it wasn’t anything political that turned me on to The Boss, it was purely a chance musical encounter: I was at a Margaritaville in Myrtle Beach, South Carolina. The cheesiest place you can be, really. I overheard a live version of “Waiting On A Sunny Day” on the restaurant radio. The cheesiest Boss song you could play (though you could debate that award goes to “Cadillac Ranch” just as easily).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something about it hooked me. His live show energy. The huge E-Street sound. Something. I went back to our vacation condo and downloaded every Springsteen album I could. From that moment, I was a Boss fan. He’s become one of my all-time favorite artists. I’ve seen him live twice and hope to again many times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if those were the only two examples of this phenomena, I wouldn’t think much of it. But I could recite similar stories of heavy distaste for many of my favorite bands/artists now: mewithoutYou, Beirut, Broken Social Scene, The National, and on and on. With varying levels of initial distaste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the strangest thing to me. Maybe I am just too skeptical. Maybe it just  takes a second and a third try to sway me around. And honestly, I can’t tell if that’s a good thing or a bad thing. Maybe it just takes that much more to convince me that something’s worth more than one listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you want to know if you have a really great idea or a hot new sound, let me take a gander. If I don’t like it, you probably have something worthy on your hands there. In the meantime, I’ll just take stock of the things I hate right now and prepare myself for a few years down the road when they’ll be the only thing I talk about.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2014/03/23/hate-before-love.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2014/03/23/hate-before-love.html</guid>
        
        <category>dad-rock</category>
        
        <category>that-sad-and-holy-glow</category>
        
        <category>we-laugh-indoors</category>
        
        <category>svbtle</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Energy Creates Energy</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-best-advice-often-comes-at-the-strangest-times-&quot;&gt;The best advice often comes at the strangest times. &lt;!-- break --&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little over 2 years ago, I found myself sitting in a cube farm in the middle of Kansas City, Missouri staring intently at a coffee cup branded with my current employer’s logo. They were all about giving away free company swag, this place was. I had t-shirts, jackets, polos and pint glasses all emblazoned with our name. But it was the coffee mug that made me chuckle. Below the company logo was a quote, one that seemed so ironic to me at that very moment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A company is known by the people it keeps.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few minutes prior, I had just been called into my boss’s office. If they didn’t get any work in soon, he said, they were going to have to let me go. This particular company’s workload ebbed and flowed with some pretty major local industries and when the work dried up, so did that cube farm. The week before I saw six fellow co-workers get the boot. I had only been there five months, I probably should’ve saw it coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the mug, I thought, what about the saying on the stupid mug? This whole first in, first out concept of hiring and laying off was so foreign to me. I grew in a small town in rural Ohio, went to college nearby and then got a job in that same small town. It was a company that really was known by the people that it kept. To the tune of 20, 30 and 40 years. My department had all of five employees when I decided to up and leave. I was very green when I started there fresh out of college. But they kept me and worked through my naivety. But after seven years of making peanuts and not advancing, though, I was ready for &lt;a href=&quot;/2010/07/05/choose-your-own-adventure.html&quot;&gt;something new&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew a few folks in KC so I stuffed my compact with just about everything I owned and drove the 750 miles to &lt;a href=&quot;/2011/07/12/on-leaving-and-lebron.html&quot;&gt;my new home&lt;/a&gt;. After riding couches for 2 1/2 months and blowing through my savings, I finally got a job at a hip, slick-looking company. I joined the ranks of about 40 other employees in my department. This definitely wasn’t small potatoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They served fresh fruit in the break-room and gave lunch &amp;amp; learn’s on staying fit. They named their conference rooms after classic rock records. We had our Christmas party in the upstairs of a popular downtown brewery. Everything but the actual work itself was pretty cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter the CEO (and the subject of this post, really). I’m not convinced he was actually involved in any of the day to day affairs but he sure brought the energy that loosely held the place together. He was the hype guy. I think that’s what made him so likable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was really, I mean, REALLY into fitness. He wasn’t just a marathon runner. He was an ultra-marathoner. Absolute insanity. Like 50+ miles in the wilderness insane. And if there’s one thing you should know about ultra-marathoners, it’s that they feel it’s their personal life debt to make sure everyone they know becomes ultra-marathoners too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guy tried really, really hard to get everyone in the office as much into running as he was. At my second interview, he popped in my boss’s office and talked to me excitedly about the fitness-crazed culture there. He gave me a copy of the book “Born To Run” and insisted it was required reading before my first day. In fact, I’m fairly convinced I was mostly hired because I am an avid cyclist. Close enough for him, I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was successful in converting several of the long time employees there into ultra-runners. Hell, he nearly convinced me to sign up for a marathon. Little did I know how much pull that probably would have got me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Energy creates energy, all you need is a spark”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…is the kind of stuff I’d hear him spout off quite frequently at those lunch and learn’s. At the time, it went in one ear and out the other. In fact, after I knew that his hip, cultured company was firing me, I wrote off every little catchphrase he said. The “brain food” in the break room, the Yellow Submarine, all of it went went out the door. Negative energy created negative energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m at my second job since leaving that company (and so are many of my fellow co-workers) but I still think about that phrase a lot. Energy creates energy. Damn, that crazy CEO was right. Potential energy is only realized when it becomes kinetic. It’s simple and it’s cyclical&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Energy is infectious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had just worked at that company for five months so I could learn that principle then I think it was worth it. It’s got me up off my butt more times than I can count. Whether it’s getting out on my bike and putting some miles in or forgoing procrastination on a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you need is a spark. It’s so true. Once you crest that hill of procrastination, laziness or whatever, you can’t be stopped. We’re all momentum driven. At least, I am. Once you get me going, you’ll be hard pressed to stop me. Writing this post was much that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried a lot of methods to increase my productivity both on and off the clock. Nothing has done more for me in the last two years than grasping this concept. Physical energy begets mental energy begets social energy begets spiritual energy…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You just have to get the ball rolling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two years later and I haven’t run a marathon yet. But I still have that stupid mug. It’s my potential energy. Maybe one day I’ll find myself a spark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;this-post-was-originally-published-here&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was originally published&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ryanstraits.svbtle.com/energy-creates-energy&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 08:25:13 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2013/06/14/energy-creates-energy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2013/06/14/energy-creates-energy.html</guid>
        
        <category>ride-on-right-on</category>
        
        <category>kc-accidental</category>
        
        <category>working-mans-blues</category>
        
        <category>my-body-is-a-cage</category>
        
        <category>svbtle</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I Work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you ever happen to catch me on my lunch break, besides munching on some tasty sourdough pretzels, you will most likely find me laboring to get to whatever the RSS equivalent of “Inbox Zero” is on this ever-expanding feed of mine. I, of course, have an elaborate system for how I make my way through the many blogs, tech journals and “what’s new” sites that I like to keep up on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One such ritual requires that I always save my two favorite technology-centered blogs for dead last, &lt;a href=&quot;http://gizmodo.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lifehacker&lt;/a&gt;. They are both excellently curated and seem to always feature articles that pique my interest on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of their more recent features revolves around interviewing &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5967582/im-anthony-casalena-founder-of-squarespace-and-this-is-how-i-work&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;various&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5965839/im-bradford-shellhammer-founder-of-fab-and-this-is-how-i-work&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;movers&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5971940/im-guy-kawasaki-and-this-is-how-i-work&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;shakers&lt;/a&gt; within the tech industry to see what their work setup is like and what keeps them staying productive. I eat this kind of stuff up, like those aforementioned pretzels I suppose, since I’m always looking for ways to become more efficient or keep on task. I’m easily distracted, so sometimes it’s nice to do what I can to eliminate those interruptions or keep them to a minimum. And the great news is, there are A TON of great apps/techniques/what-have-you hitting the interwebs every day that are armed and ready to help fight those distractions right along side me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, since Lifehacker isn’t going to be interviewing lowly ol’ me any time soon, I went ahead and decided to interview myself and share some of the tips and tricks I use to keep me pointed in the right direction both at work and at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name:&lt;/strong&gt; Ryan Straits&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Occupation:&lt;/strong&gt; Product Line (Mechanical) Engineer, Marlen International, Overland Park, KS&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Kansas City, MO&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Current computer:&lt;/strong&gt; Lenovo W530 Thinkpad w/ Docking Station &amp;amp; dual 24” displays (Work), 24” iMac (Home)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Current mobile device:&lt;/strong&gt; iPhone 5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What apps/software/tools can’t you live without?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excel. I do just about everything in it and it’s my lifesaver. From budgets to listing out objectives &amp;amp; action items for managing projects, I don’t go a day without using it. I also just started using a pretty great website/app called &lt;a href=&quot;https://workflowy.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Workflowy&lt;/a&gt; to stay organized. It’s helped me get all my thoughts in one place. On the days I’m feeling particularly unfocused, I resort to using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.focusboosterapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Focus Booster&lt;/a&gt;, which is one of the slickest &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.focusboosterapp.com/the-pomodoro-technique&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pomodoro technique&lt;/a&gt; apps that I’ve come across.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For hardware, since Autodesk Inventor is the main program I’m working in all day, my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.3dconnexion.com/products/spacenavigator.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Space Navigator&lt;/a&gt; is essential. It’s any 3D modeler’s best friend. I’m also a big fan of using trackball mice. I have one at home and at work. They’re annoying for the uninitiated but once you start using one, you’ll never go back to traditional mice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Home Screen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your best time-saving shortcut/life hack?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became a much more efficient person the day I discovered that apps like &lt;a href=&quot;http://getpocket.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; exist. I used to get stuck feeling forced to rush through reading articles or websites that I didn’t have time to check out. Pocket allows me to save that stuff for later when I really have the time to dive into them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a more general sense, I am a very big systems guy. I’m fairly forgetful, so I’ve learned to structure menial tasks so that I don’t forget to do them. Ask my wife, I have pretty much the same routine every day. It may seem boring, but it allows my mind to think about all the other things I need to do rather than worry about whether I forgot to brush my teeth or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your favorite to-do list manager?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to give Apple’s Reminders it’s best shot since it’s integrated into iOS and OSX so heavily. But it’s annoying sync glitches eventually forced me to start auditioning replacements. I tried several popular choices including &lt;a href=&quot;https://cheddarapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cheddar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.6wunderkinder.com/wunderlist&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wunderlist&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://astrid.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Astrid&lt;/a&gt; but found them all lacking in different ways. I also didn’t want to lay down hard-earned cash for top-rated apps like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.realmacsoftware.com/clear/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Clear&lt;/a&gt; when I knew I could find a decent free one out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I eventually settled on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.any.do/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Any.DO&lt;/a&gt;. It’s got a pretty slick iOS app and a full-featured Chrome extension to go with it. Since I usually always have Chrome open during the day, Any.DO’s integration with it is priceless. I also like that I can plan out projects using Workflowy and then just select a line item, right-click and add it right to a to-do list in Any.DO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your workspace like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to think I keep a pretty clutter-free workspace but I often don’t have as much time as I’d like to keep things in their proper place. If I get done with a certain task near the end of the day and don’t have time to start another I’ll usually use the remaining part of the work day to tidy up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a big fan of &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5984548/boost-your-productivity-by-adjusting-your-workspaces-lighting-and-temperature&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;natural lighting and an ergonomic environment&lt;/a&gt; and believe that humans are their most productive when they have ample amounts of both. As you can see from the picture below, I don’t get much of either in my current broom closet of an office. However, I am thankful for the 4 walls and door that I do have, though. Since 2005, I have been to 3 different jobs and all 3 were in cubicles. This was my first job back in an office since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be short-lived, however, as my company is relocating to a new facility in Riverside, MO next month. It’s brand new and filled with, you guessed it, cubicles. I’m sure the newness of the office will be great, but I’ll miss the brief year or so that I got to spend in a closed off space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/work-setup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Work&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/home-setup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Home&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you listen to while you work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can usually always find me with at least one earbud in at work. They were (and will be) my only walls in Cubeville. I have a few podcasts I keep up on (mostly sports in nature like Fantasy Focus Football &amp;amp; The BS Report). Music-wise, I used to have just a few of my favorite new albums stashed on my iPhone or put up with Spotify’s infernal ads. Recently though, I discovered the wonder that is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.subsonic.org/pages/index.jsp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Subsonic&lt;/a&gt;. It takes some networking know-how but I now have my entire music collection (all 200GB worth) available to me on my phone and my work PC. For free. It’s revolutionized my music-listening world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Besides your phone and computer, what gadget can’t you live without?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, my wife and I can’t live without the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foscam.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Foscam&lt;/a&gt; security camera that we set up as a baby monitor. I again used a little network trickery to set it up so that we can view it anywhere we’re at, either on our phones or the web. It’s been great for keeping an eye on Audrey and my wife loves it. It was an all together cheap solution compared to many of the over-priced baby monitor systems out there. We spent less than $100 for the camera and the apps for our phones/iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your sleep routine like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to get at least 6 hours a night. 7 is optimal. I’m usually in bed by 11:30 and up by 6am. I’m going to start experimenting with some of these “sleep cycle” alarm apps to see if they’re worth the hype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What everyday thing are you better at than anyone else?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pretty good at creating efficient systems of getting things done and then sticking with that system. I’ll also continue to prove it out to make sure it’s the best solution possible. I do this with my daily commute. I’m constantly looking for the quickest way there and back. I’m never content to just stick with one route. There’s always got to be a faster way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the best advice you’ve ever received?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Energy creates energy. Potential is only realized when it becomes kinetic. It’s simple and it’s cyclical. I’m very momentum-driven and I sometimes struggle with initiation and getting things started, so this is huge for me. If I can just push past that initial opposing force of procrastination/laziness/whatever, then I can’t be stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything else you want to share with readers?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a &lt;a href=&quot;/2008/03/27/im-a-serial-archivist.html&quot;&gt;serial archivist&lt;/a&gt;. I love archiving and organizing. For Christmas this year, my father-in-law got me a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getdoxie.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Doxie&lt;/a&gt; document scanner. Coupled with &lt;a href=&quot;http://evernote.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt;, I’m using it to digitize my entire filing cabinet at some point in 2013. And I couldn’t be more excited about it. I have it all mapped out in Workflowy. And I’ll be getting to it right after I finish reorganizing my entire music collection (to better work with Subsonic) and then my entire media collection. Priorities, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 04:33:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2013/02/18/how-i-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2013/02/18/how-i-work.html</guid>
        
        <category>futures</category>
        
        <category>that-sad-and-holy-glow</category>
        
        <category>soul-driver</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How To Know You're From Kansas City</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;About nine years ago when I still lived in Ohio, two of my good friends at the time just so happened to be from Missouri and Kansas. It’s kind of a long story how they got there, but it could be said that they found a lot of our local idiosyncrasies hilarious. One day they decided to compile a  fairly smarting list of these quirky traits and emailed it to all of their Ohio friends for a good laugh (it was 2003, we emailed a lot back then). They wrote it all under the moniker “The MO-KAN Connection”.
&lt;!-- break --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll admit, I didn’t take it as kindly then as I do looking back on it now. It was pretty darn funny. But sometimes it’s not very much fun to listen to someone with an outside perspective make jokes about “your town” or “your upbringing”. I was born and raised in T-County (Tuscarawas County for long, and yea they made fun of the name too), so sometimes I just didn’t know any different. It’s good every now and then to take a look at things from a different point of view (keep this in mind as you continue reading).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cuz now, the tables have turned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s nine years later, and I’ve been living in Kansas City for over two years. Both those friends of mine have moved back to the Greater Kansas City area as well, so it’s time for me to give my own little dose of perspective on their home city/state (one of them is actually from Springfield but many of these still apply). Now granted, KC may not be as quirky as Ohio Amish country, I’ll give you that. But you guys still do some pretty crazy stuff out here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here goes, make sure to read this knowing the love behind which it was crafted. Also, read it with humility. Cuz it’s all preeeeeeetty much true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-know-youre-from-kansas-city-if&quot;&gt;You know you’re from Kansas City if…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You think KU vs. MU is one of the most storied rivalries in college sports.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can’t wait to take out-of-town guests to see the spectacle that is The Plaza.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You call two slabs of meat on a plain piece of white bread with a dollop of BBQ sauce and a pickle on the side “good BBQ”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You think people from Johnson County can drive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You call a trip to the Ozarks “a vacation”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You don’t think it’s weird that the “University of Kansas” and the “University of Missouri” are abbreviated KU &amp;amp; MU instead of UK &amp;amp; UM.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You don’t understand why the previous statement was included in this list.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re considering moving from the suburbs to the city just so you’ll be assured of getting Google Fiber.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You actually enjoy the ketchup &amp;amp; mustard color scheme that the Chiefs have employed since that combination of colors actually looked good together back in nineteen-NEVER.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You really did think it was “Our Time”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You place the word “highway” after the road it is referring to instead of before like the rest of America, e.g. “71 highway”, “69 highway”, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ve never heard of a drive-thru liquor store.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You could lead someone right to Truman’s birthplace like the whole of your existence depends on you knowing this information.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can name with astounding certainty which Kansas City news anchors are gay.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You defy all pronunciation rules and logic by saying the word ornery (oRn-er-y) like this: “on-ree”. (Ohio friends: Yes, that’s really how they say it)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Have you been to the Plaza yet? You’ve got to check out the Plaza.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You actually believe that you get better cell reception on your Sprint phone just because their world headquarters is in OP.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You know the best times to avoid the lines at Oklahoma Joe’s.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ve been mugged at least once.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your car has been broken into at least once.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your house has been broken into at least once.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ve never questioned why such a ridiculously asinine statement like “Rock Chalk Jayhawk” is your school’s battle cry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You know what “The Triangle” is and when to avoid it at all costs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You think that arguing with your buddies “which KC restaurant has the best BBQ in the city?” is a wise use of your time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You know exactly where The Goodfoot is playing tonight. Because it’s the exact same place they played at last week.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You will only fill up your car at a Quik Trip.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You give directions to your home by mentioning the nearest recognizable intersection, e.g. “95th &amp;amp; Metcalf”, “75th &amp;amp; Wornall”, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You consider the 6th inning sing-along to “Friends in Low Places” a fine Kauffman Stadium tradition, even though Garth Brooks isn’t from Kansas City and it JUST MAKES NO SENSE WHATSOEVER.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You think Lee’s Summit is just a short drive away.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Seriously, you haven’t been to the Plaza? We need to take you to the Plaza.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You root for the Chiefs, the Cardinals and whichever NBA team your favorite KU player is currently on. And you can’t understand why anyone would ever want to root for all the pro sports teams from just ONE city.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You call anything north of the river the “Northland”. And you REFUSE to ever go there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re not-so-secretly proud that Missouri is now considered by many to be the Meth Capital of the World.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ve pronounced it “Missour-uh” at some point in your life.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You didn’t know that Hyvee and PriceChopper weren’t nationally recognized grocery chains until you just read this sentence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You consider 90° to be a nice, breezy summer day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You regularly go on something you call “float trips” in the summer. These consist of a river, some form of flotation device and a massive amount of alcohol.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your claim to fame is that you went to the same high school as Paul Rudd, Jason Sudeikis and that guy from Modern Family.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You got a little bit too excited when Trader Joe’s opened.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You actually root for the UMKC ‘Roos at whatever sporting events they compete in. No really though, what sporting events do they compete in?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You feel that “Schlitterbahn” is a great name for a water park.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You call moving to Johnson County “selling out”. But you do it anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You actually know someone who is sending their kids through the Kansas City school district.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The highlight of a Royals game for you is the tailgating you do beforehand.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You think it’s normal to tailgate before a baseball game.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You freak out about getting your hands on some Boulevard Chocolate Ale, even though you think it tastes like liquefied Hershey bars.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Did you know Tech N9ne is from Kansas City?” “Umm, who?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You think the Chiefs are going to contend this year.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you go out of town you tell people the name of the suburb you’re from (instead of just saying you’re from “Kansas City”), as if they’ve ever heard of it!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re not really offended by this list because you’ve found yourself agreeing with so much of it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With love,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The T-County connection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find a copy of my buddies’ list, &lt;strong&gt;“You Know You’re From T-County If…“&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/2003/02/21/014.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, on my old Xanga site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2012/07/26/how-to-know-youre-from-kansas-city.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2012/07/26/how-to-know-youre-from-kansas-city.html</guid>
        
        <category>kc-accidental</category>
        
        <category>we-laugh-indoors</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On Leaving And Lebron</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a year now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One year ago last Wednesday, I packed up everything I could fit into a little, blue Mazda and headed west. It was one of the hardest things I’ll probably ever do in my life. Leaving my family, my friends and the only life I had known for the last 28 and half years wasn’t an easy call. But there I was, on July 6th, 2010, watching my parents fade away in my rearview as I set a course for the great unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or Kansas City, as the dot on my GPS map insisted on informing me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days later, you decided it was time to leave Ohio too. But with much bigger fanfare, naturally. Hours of news-cycle time, rampant speculation, and a much-hyped TV special were all dedicated to your big “Decision”. Most Ohioans weren’t too worried. I mean, how could you leave your &lt;em&gt;home&lt;/em&gt;? You were our “chosen one”, after all. You were the savior of Cleveland sports. The one to finally bring a championship to our hard-luck city. Fate had finally shone down upon us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was our time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We grew up with you. I, personally, saw you play three of your high school championship games at the state tournaments. I was never a particularly big basketball fan, but you had a way of igniting a passion for the game out of indifference. You turned arenas electric. We were all witnesses. And then, the impossible happened: the lowly Cavaliers lucked into taking you 1st in the draft. A once-in-a-generation talent &lt;em&gt;from our area&lt;/em&gt; coming back to &lt;em&gt;represent our area&lt;/em&gt; to the rest of the country? Northeast Ohio was abuzz. It was too good to be true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/news_poster-witness-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Quitness&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And boy, you sure knew how to put on a show. My dad bought season tickets to your games even though we lived an hour and a half away. My parents, especially, loved going to watch you play. You turned &lt;em&gt;my mom&lt;/em&gt; into a basketball fan. The games she actually let me go to with my dad will be remembered as some of the best sports experiences of my life. You turned 20,562 screaming fans into a close-knit community every night. There just wasn’t anything like it. With the game on the line, we looked to you. We knew you could “turn it on” whenever you wanted and take over the game. The rest of the team just stood and watched you work your magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/cavs-fam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cavs in my blood&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was, until, they started talking about New York. The playoff losses started mounting. The pressure on you to win now started growing. We expected you to stay, to keep fighting for your city. You &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fannation.com/truth_and_rumors/view/174990-lebrons-goal-bring-title-to-cleveland&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said it yourself&lt;/a&gt;, you weren’t going to stop until you brought home a championship to the city of Cleveland. Let ESPN talk all they want, we’d say, you wouldn’t &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; leave Ohio before you did, would you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, however, called it all along. You were going to leave. This &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; Cleveland we’re talking about, the most down-trodden sports city in the entire country. This is just the way things go here. In Ohio, we’re born defeatist. And because of it, nearly everyone in our generation is looking for a ticket out. Maybe you were just looking for your chance all along? The signs were there: the Yankees hats, your love for the Cowboys. I mean, really? You never wanted to make this your home, did you? We should have known better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first got the inkling to leave in the winter of 2009. I had just moved out on my own for the first time. My own apartment, all to myself. I was honestly just hoping to find some peace in living alone. It never came. Instead, I grew more introverted as my friends all got married or moved away. I was 27 with the specter of 30 fast approaching. The pressure was mounting to grow up fast: get married, buy a house, in whatever order you’d like. But I had exhausted all my options in Ohio. I was &lt;a href=&quot;/2010/7/5/choose-your-own-adventure.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;spinning my wheels&lt;/a&gt;. After a year of looking at possibilities: recording school in Florida, the always enticing idea of Californ-i-a, etc., I started working up the nerve it would take to actually move away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had always said I’d one day break free of the captive orbit that Ohio kept us all in. She’s an enchanter, though, and you need a darn fine reason for her to let you go. Luckily, mine drove to Ohio and met me at a youth rally I was leading praise at on New Year’s Day 2010. And she just so happened to be from Kansas City. One very option I had &lt;a href=&quot;/2010/7/5/choose-your-own-adventure.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;already been considering&lt;/a&gt;. She was my tipping point. It was then just a matter of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six months later, I was on the road to Kansas City with no job or place to stay ahead of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave my “decision” to my parents in their kitchen after one of my mom’s regular, delicious home-cooked meals. She fought back tears but said she understood. She wanted me to be happy and knew I wasn’t. I fought back tears when she asked if I’d ever consider moving back. I told my close friends in the same living room we usually talked about Jesus and drank beers. I told my niece on our back porch before she was old enough to understand what I was saying. I asked her to not forget about me when I’m gone. Those are memories I’ll always hold dear. Ones that I still can’t shake without crying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There weren’t any TV cameras, or captive audiences, or charities, or cheesy flannel shirts (well, maybe a few flannel shirts). I didn’t have the luxury of playing soft-toss with Jim Gray at some remote location in Greenwich, Connecticut (I mean, c’mon…New England?). No, there wasn’t a whole wide world of sports waiting to hear what I had decided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/lebron-decision.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dat flannel tho...&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at &lt;em&gt;least&lt;/em&gt; there was heartache. It broke my heart to leave Ohio. It broke my heart to feel like I was letting my family down by moving away. It broke my heart to know that I wouldn’t be living life beside these people anymore. That I wouldn’t be able to just drop by after work to talk and eat dinner with my parents. That I wouldn’t be going to Grandma’s after church on Sundays anymore. God had knit our hearts so close together for so many years and now our relationship would only exist on the other end of a telephone or computer screen. &lt;em&gt;That&lt;/em&gt; is heartbreaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it’s standard to write about all the favorite places that you’ll miss in your home state once you move away. But I don’t have a lot of “favorite places” in Ohio. I just have a lot of favorite &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt; in Ohio. And the times and places I’ll remember most are almost always tied to the people that I was able to share them with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know what else was heartbreaking? Watching your so-called “Decision” from the bar of a seafood restaurant on the outskirts of Kansas City. Feeling the hope of an entire region fade away on national television from 800 miles away is heartbreaking. I knew right then what the reaction would be. And I, for one, was glad I wasn’t in Ohio to see it first-hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Here we go again.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being out here for the aftermath has made me realize that no one outside of Ohio really gets it. It’s a situation that is so uniquely ours. I watched you play a preseason game here in KC while my emotions were still raw. A friend made me a sign. I wore all Cleveland garb, screamed my lungs out in derision, and embarrassed all my friends. I’m sure it was nothing like being in Cleveland for your first game back at The Q, but it sure was cathartic. ”Get over it, free agents leave,” my new KC friends would say. No, not this one. It’s bigger than that. He’s supposed to understand. He’s one of &lt;em&gt;us&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or at least we &lt;em&gt;thought&lt;/em&gt; you were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/lebron-heated.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Heat check&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think Dan Wetzel of Yahoo Sports put the whole thing in &lt;a href=&quot;http://sports.yahoo.com/nba/news;_ylt=AoWfdJHNo5Q7zT3ZweCYfDW8vLYF?slug=dw-wetzel_cleveland_laughs_at_lebron_james_061211&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;perspective&lt;/a&gt; best:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;No city has lost like this one, not a single major professional sports championship since 1964, when the Browns won a pre-Super Bowl NFL title. You’d have to be in your mid-50s to remember it. Cleveland’s modern sports memories are defined in short terms, as if elaborating is just too painful: The Drive, The Fumble, The Shot, The Move and, of course, The Decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You want collapses? The 1997 World Series is as bad as anything the Cubs or Red Sox ever dealt with. It’s just this city doesn’t have the media poets to chronicle it like Chicago or Boston. You want the true gut punch? Their beloved Browns moved to Baltimore only to finally get their act together and win a Super Bowl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And then there was this, LeBron James, the local kid from Akron, the one who claimed he understood your heartache, the one you defended for years, the one that was finally going to deliver sporting glory. He bails for some fair-weather sports town and an arena full of white-covered chairs with pretty people who can’t even be bothered to watch the game while it’s going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did it break your heart to leave Ohio? I know it didn’t break your heart to leave Cleveland. The way you left tells us that much. Your big Lithuanian friend &lt;em&gt;who didn’t even grow up in America&lt;/em&gt;, let alone Cleveland, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.waitingfornextyear.com/2010/08/zydrunas-ilgauskas-thanks-fans-in-sunday-morning-ad/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;showed everyone&lt;/a&gt; how you leave a beloved city with class: “I…hope you realize that Cleveland will always be home to me.” You’d do well to take notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is, we glossed over your arrogance. The showboating, the posturing, the egotism, the chalk toss. It was downplayed because you were a “hometown” boy. We saw it and just laughed it off. And that’s on us. But now, it’s on you. We’ve grieved, but we’re &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P3pbLyHCOCo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;moving on&lt;/a&gt;. Akron might take you back, but Ohio never will. You’ve taken your place in the long list of dark spots in Cleveland’s sports history. Did you really envision it turning out any differently? If you really were ashamed of claiming Ohio as your home, you wouldn’t have to worry about it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ohio is ashamed of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a year and I think I’ve finally come to terms with leaving Ohio. I might’ve just come to terms with you leaving too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t blame you for wanting to leave Ohio. I mean, look at me, I left too. No, I blame you for the way you left. And that’s coming from a guy who tried his best to leave the right way. I gave my job a two-month notice. I got my affairs in order. I wanted to give people time to adjust. But really, I think I was the one who needed the adjustment time. It was a transition. I needed time to grieve and let people grieve. You don’t just pull the rug out from under people’s feet. Not when the particular people you’re hoodwinking have had such a sorry history of similar close-calls and let-downs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve built up so many defense mechanisms over the years as Ohioans, ones that you seemed to have deliberately played into. We have it in our blood to be confidently optimistic and then curse the wind when the same thing happens &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cleveland_Browns_relocation_controversy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;over&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1997_World_Series&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;over&lt;/a&gt; again. We build up just enough hope so that there’s a substantial enough amount to get dashed away later. Sarcasm has become engrained in our way of life. We’re cocky to the Steelers fans, to the Celtics fans, to the Yankees &amp;amp; Red Sox fans and then just fall back to “Well, there’s always next year!” when the cycle continues. Whole &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.waitingfornextyear.com/2011/07/hurry-up-wait-and-be-patient-with-browns/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;websites&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.clevelandfrowns.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;internet followings&lt;/a&gt; have grown out of this effort in futility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe me, I wanted to leave all that negativity behind too. But leaving has given me a new love for my home state. It’s that fond love that grows with distance. And I bet it’s growing in you now too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirteen hours on the road by yourself gives you just enough time to get excited about what you’re doing, then doubt what you’re doing, and then get excited all over again. My mood swings on that never-ending drive through the Plains were most likely dictated by the ups and downs of the wide array of music I had put into playlists for the long journey out. Luckily, it kept me distracted just long enough from thinking about how I honestly didn’t know where I would be staying when I got out to Kansas City. I just knew that it’s where I needed to be. A few rather kind folks decided to take me in. I stayed on my best friend’s couch for a night. And then transferred my meager belongings into the den of a house that belonged to three guys I barely knew. They graciously allowed me to stay there until I landed a job in my new home city. That stay would last for just under three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t know it then, but I had just happened into one of the most amazing group of friends that I’ve ever been apart of. Yes, I had to make the heart-rending decision to leave my family and friends back in Ohio. But I met, dated, and am going to marry the girl of my dreams out here in KC in three months. She wound up being a pretty good reason to leave Ohio. The price was steep, but I’d say it was a fairly even trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, can you say the same thing? Was it worth it? I’ll be honest, I rooted for you to lose. And just about all of Ohio was darn happy when you did. Even if you would have pulled out some late-game magic like you always seemed to do for us, would it have been as fulfilling? Wouldn’t it have been &lt;em&gt;that much sweeter&lt;/em&gt; if you were winning it all for Cleveland? Wouldn’t that be a much greater cause? It sure looks like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/07/11/lebron-james-popularity-all-time-low_n_894819.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rest of America&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://sports.espn.go.com/nba/news/story?id=5575810&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;thinks so&lt;/a&gt;. But hey, you made your choice. And I made mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it turned out to be the best one I’ve ever made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“All the people that was rooting on me to fail, at the end of the day they have to wake up tomorrow and have the same life that they had before they woke up today,” James said. “They have the same personal problems they had today. I’m going to continue to live the way I want to live and continue to do the things that I want to do with me and my family and be happy with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“They can get a few days or a few months or whatever the case may be on being happy about not only myself, but the Miami Heat not accomplishing their goal. But they have to get back to the real world at some point.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, now &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; have to get back to the real world. We already live here. The real world of making a decision and having to stick with it. There’s no turning back. It’s I-70 westbound straight into the setting sun with only pictures of your family and the hope of what lies on the other side to keep you going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But whatever you have to say to help you sleep at night. You’ve made your bed. You chose and you lost. But hey, coming from Ohio you should be pretty familiar with that empty feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, well, there’s always next year.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 03:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2011/07/12/on-leaving-and-lebron.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2011/07/12/on-leaving-and-lebron.html</guid>
        
        <category>bloodbuzz-ohio</category>
        
        <category>fambly</category>
        
        <category>all-is-a-game</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Facebook Is The Mark Of The Beast</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I mean, is there really any doubt?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know one thing, I used to write things on the internet. Sometimes they were interesting, sometimes they were complete drivel. But the key was, I wrote them. I sat down at my computer, I opened a blog post window and I wrote.
These days, I’m more likely to open a rapid succession of Facebook and Twitter windows and read things other people have written. Some of them interesting, some complete drivel. I still write, but it’s more fragments and pieces of thoughts than what I would have otherwise have formed into complete phrases within a blog post a few years back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each tweet, each status update have given me a sense of completion, but they’re just a taste. They’re nothing like that thrill of hitting the “publish” button on a long-form work that you’ve given serious thought and contemplation to. I’m sure it’s somewhere near what a novelist feels when they hit the return key at the end of a completed chapter. It’s that sense of fear in knowing your thoughts will be read, but also, that satisfaction in knowing you’ve created something and you’ve put yourself out there to be critiqued. And well, that counts for something, doesn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this is a post about how I haven’t posted. And my struggle to figure out why. I’ve had an idea of something to write for going on a year now. And I just haven’t written it. This would have bothered me a few years ago. Back then, I &lt;a href=&quot;/tag/xanga&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wrote something&lt;/a&gt; just about every day. It was more of a journal of my day’s events than anything. But I took great care to fashion each post. I designed the site with great attention to detail. I took a lot of pride in my silly, little Xanga page. And now I laugh a lot when I go back and read through it. But the point is, it’s still there. You can still go and read all the thoughts, emotions and events of my life for the span of well over three years. It’s riveting material, let me forewarn you. Wikipedia rabbit-trails have nothing on my Xanga site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also a post about how I’m not quitting Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I’ve read blog posts about this sort of phenomena before. And usually all of them end with the author resigning himself to quitting Facebook/Twitter and only posting on their blogs from here on out. That’s great and all, except for the mere fact that no one will read anything you’ll write from here on out. There are a few exceptions, but on the whole everyone looks to Facebook to see what’s going on in their world. Facebook (and Twitter to a lesser extent) has become the only online social hub. We’ve all taken it’s mark. There is no socializing outside it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a bit drastic, I know. But it’s the future, and I’ve accepted that. It grieves me a little that sites like Xanga aren’t the social epicenter anymore. But I get why they died, they weren’t instant enough. They had a lazy pace to them. But I think it was that lazy pace that made it easier for deliberate thinkers like me to keep stride with our quicker-witted online peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet is just getting so fast. And I can’t keep up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I log on, read about everyone else’s day, maybe type a few words and then close up shop. When I had my Xanga, life was the only thing that kept me from updating it. These days, it’s the internet that keeps me from updating about my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose I could just resolve myself to write more. And I’m going to do my best (starting with that post I’ve been thinking up for about a year). After all, my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birkman.com/birkmanMethod/whatIsTheBirkmanMethod.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Birkman report&lt;/a&gt; told me that, above all, I’m a “Literary”-type, and that I’m not completely fulfilled unless I’m consistently writing or doing something close to it. The fact remains, though: the internet has changed. And so too, must my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to anyone who has stuck around to read my infrequent writings on this site, I certainly appreciate your patience. I truly hope to get to a post of more substance shortly (it’s relevancy window is closing rapidly).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then…completion is just a click away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. - In this same online writing vein, a few friends and I have started an online newspaper detailing the insignificant minutiae of our daily lives. It’s more for us than you but it’s a good time regardless. It’s called “The 6th Degree”, and you can check it out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.the-6th-degree.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;note-this-was-originally-posted-on-an-old-squarespace-blog-of-mine-most-of-the-references-links-and-jokes-are-probably-dead&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This was originally posted on an old Squarespace blog of mine. Most of the references, links and jokes are probably dead.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2011/07/05/facebook-is-the-mark-of-the-beast.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2011/07/05/facebook-is-the-mark-of-the-beast.html</guid>
        
        <category>that-sad-and-holy-glow</category>
        
        <category>wolf-am-i</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
