<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ghost States</title>
    <description>&lt;i&gt;The art of the in-between&lt;/i&gt;
</description>
    <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.ryanstraits.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 13:24:42 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 13:24:42 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hate Before Love</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have this quirk. I tend to hate things that I wind up falling in love with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It happens a lot with new apps. I think an idea is stupid and write it off, then it comes back around to woo me. Twitter is one example. I &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ryanstraits/statuses/789269312&quot; title=&quot;First Tweet&quot;&gt;signed up in 2008&lt;/a&gt;, but didn’t start using it until 2010. Now it’s the first app I go to on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s happened even more often with music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back around 2000, a good friend wanted me to download &amp;amp; burn him a copy of this new British band he had just heard of. For some reason, I instantly couldn’t stand them. Something about their sound irked me, like they were just sampling The Bends era Radiohead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years later, I heard “In My Place” on a TV show and had to know what band it was. Well, it was obviously Coldplay. I had missed the boat, they were pretty good. After that, I couldn’t get enough. And then I had to get caught up on Parachutes, which everyone was sick of back in 2000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there was Springsteen. I didn’t have any friends into The Boss, I just hated him on mostly political grounds. I was a fairly heavy conservative back around 2004 and he was prominent in the Democratic opposition to The Iraq War and George W. Bush. Something about his political activism struck me the wrong way, so I wrote him and his American-blue-collar-rock off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to the spring of 2008. I had just started course-correcting myself back to being a moderate. I was beginning to think towards voting for Barack Obama. But it wasn’t anything political that turned me on to The Boss, it was purely a chance musical encounter: I was at a Margaritaville in Myrtle Beach, South Carolina. The cheesiest place you can be, really. I overheard a live version of “Waiting On A Sunny Day” on the restaurant radio. The cheesiest Boss song you could play (though you could debate that award goes to “Cadillac Ranch” just as easily).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something about it hooked me. His live show energy. The huge E-Street sound. Something. I went back to our vacation condo and downloaded every Springsteen album I could. From that moment, I was a Boss fan. He’s become one of my all-time favorite artists. I’ve seen him live twice and hope to again many times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if those were the only two examples of this phenomena, I wouldn’t think much of it. But I could recite similar stories of heavy distaste for many of my favorite bands/artists now: mewithoutYou, Beirut, Broken Social Scene, The National, and on and on. With varying levels of initial distaste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the strangest thing to me. Maybe I am just too skeptical. Maybe it just  takes a second and a third try to sway me around. And honestly, I can’t tell if that’s a good thing or a bad thing. Maybe it just takes that much more to convince me that something’s worth more than one listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you want to know if you have a really great idea or a hot new sound, let me take a gander. If I don’t like it, you probably have something worthy on your hands there. In the meantime, I’ll just take stock of the things I hate right now and prepare myself for a few years down the road when they’ll be the only thing I talk about.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2014/03/23/hate-before-love.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2014/03/23/hate-before-love.html</guid>
        
        <category>dad-rock</category>
        
        <category>that-sad-and-holy-glow</category>
        
        <category>we-laugh-indoors</category>
        
        <category>svbtle</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I Work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you ever happen to catch me on my lunch break, besides munching on some tasty sourdough pretzels, you will most likely find me laboring to get to whatever the RSS equivalent of “Inbox Zero” is on this ever-expanding feed of mine. I, of course, have an elaborate system for how I make my way through the many blogs, tech journals and “what’s new” sites that I like to keep up on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One such ritual requires that I always save my two favorite technology-centered blogs for dead last, &lt;a href=&quot;http://gizmodo.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lifehacker&lt;/a&gt;. They are both excellently curated and seem to always feature articles that pique my interest on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of their more recent features revolves around interviewing &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5967582/im-anthony-casalena-founder-of-squarespace-and-this-is-how-i-work&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;various&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5965839/im-bradford-shellhammer-founder-of-fab-and-this-is-how-i-work&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;movers&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5971940/im-guy-kawasaki-and-this-is-how-i-work&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;shakers&lt;/a&gt; within the tech industry to see what their work setup is like and what keeps them staying productive. I eat this kind of stuff up, like those aforementioned pretzels I suppose, since I’m always looking for ways to become more efficient or keep on task. I’m easily distracted, so sometimes it’s nice to do what I can to eliminate those interruptions or keep them to a minimum. And the great news is, there are A TON of great apps/techniques/what-have-you hitting the interwebs every day that are armed and ready to help fight those distractions right along side me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, since Lifehacker isn’t going to be interviewing lowly ol’ me any time soon, I went ahead and decided to interview myself and share some of the tips and tricks I use to keep me pointed in the right direction both at work and at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name:&lt;/strong&gt; Ryan Straits&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Occupation:&lt;/strong&gt; Product Line (Mechanical) Engineer, Marlen International, Overland Park, KS&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Kansas City, MO&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Current computer:&lt;/strong&gt; Lenovo W530 Thinkpad w/ Docking Station &amp;amp; dual 24” displays (Work), 24” iMac (Home)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Current mobile device:&lt;/strong&gt; iPhone 5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What apps/software/tools can’t you live without?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excel. I do just about everything in it and it’s my lifesaver. From budgets to listing out objectives &amp;amp; action items for managing projects, I don’t go a day without using it. I also just started using a pretty great website/app called &lt;a href=&quot;https://workflowy.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Workflowy&lt;/a&gt; to stay organized. It’s helped me get all my thoughts in one place. On the days I’m feeling particularly unfocused, I resort to using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.focusboosterapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Focus Booster&lt;/a&gt;, which is one of the slickest &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.focusboosterapp.com/the-pomodoro-technique&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pomodoro technique&lt;/a&gt; apps that I’ve come across.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For hardware, since Autodesk Inventor is the main program I’m working in all day, my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.3dconnexion.com/products/spacenavigator.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Space Navigator&lt;/a&gt; is essential. It’s any 3D modeler’s best friend. I’m also a big fan of using trackball mice. I have one at home and at work. They’re annoying for the uninitiated but once you start using one, you’ll never go back to traditional mice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Home Screen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your best time-saving shortcut/life hack?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became a much more efficient person the day I discovered that apps like &lt;a href=&quot;http://getpocket.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; exist. I used to get stuck feeling forced to rush through reading articles or websites that I didn’t have time to check out. Pocket allows me to save that stuff for later when I really have the time to dive into them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a more general sense, I am a very big systems guy. I’m fairly forgetful, so I’ve learned to structure menial tasks so that I don’t forget to do them. Ask my wife, I have pretty much the same routine every day. It may seem boring, but it allows my mind to think about all the other things I need to do rather than worry about whether I forgot to brush my teeth or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your favorite to-do list manager?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to give Apple’s Reminders it’s best shot since it’s integrated into iOS and OSX so heavily. But it’s annoying sync glitches eventually forced me to start auditioning replacements. I tried several popular choices including &lt;a href=&quot;https://cheddarapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cheddar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.6wunderkinder.com/wunderlist&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wunderlist&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://astrid.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Astrid&lt;/a&gt; but found them all lacking in different ways. I also didn’t want to lay down hard-earned cash for top-rated apps like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.realmacsoftware.com/clear/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Clear&lt;/a&gt; when I knew I could find a decent free one out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I eventually settled on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.any.do/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Any.DO&lt;/a&gt;. It’s got a pretty slick iOS app and a full-featured Chrome extension to go with it. Since I usually always have Chrome open during the day, Any.DO’s integration with it is priceless. I also like that I can plan out projects using Workflowy and then just select a line item, right-click and add it right to a to-do list in Any.DO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your workspace like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to think I keep a pretty clutter-free workspace but I often don’t have as much time as I’d like to keep things in their proper place. If I get done with a certain task near the end of the day and don’t have time to start another I’ll usually use the remaining part of the work day to tidy up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a big fan of &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5984548/boost-your-productivity-by-adjusting-your-workspaces-lighting-and-temperature&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;natural lighting and an ergonomic environment&lt;/a&gt; and believe that humans are their most productive when they have ample amounts of both. As you can see from the picture below, I don’t get much of either in my current broom closet of an office. However, I am thankful for the 4 walls and door that I do have, though. Since 2005, I have been to 3 different jobs and all 3 were in cubicles. This was my first job back in an office since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be short-lived, however, as my company is relocating to a new facility in Riverside, MO next month. It’s brand new and filled with, you guessed it, cubicles. I’m sure the newness of the office will be great, but I’ll miss the brief year or so that I got to spend in a closed off space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/work-setup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Work&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/home-setup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Home&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you listen to while you work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can usually always find me with at least one earbud in at work. They were (and will be) my only walls in Cubeville. I have a few podcasts I keep up on (mostly sports in nature like Fantasy Focus Football &amp;amp; The BS Report). Music-wise, I used to have just a few of my favorite new albums stashed on my iPhone or put up with Spotify’s infernal ads. Recently though, I discovered the wonder that is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.subsonic.org/pages/index.jsp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Subsonic&lt;/a&gt;. It takes some networking know-how but I now have my entire music collection (all 200GB worth) available to me on my phone and my work PC. For free. It’s revolutionized my music-listening world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Besides your phone and computer, what gadget can’t you live without?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, my wife and I can’t live without the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foscam.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Foscam&lt;/a&gt; security camera that we set up as a baby monitor. I again used a little network trickery to set it up so that we can view it anywhere we’re at, either on our phones or the web. It’s been great for keeping an eye on Audrey and my wife loves it. It was an all together cheap solution compared to many of the over-priced baby monitor systems out there. We spent less than $100 for the camera and the apps for our phones/iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your sleep routine like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to get at least 6 hours a night. 7 is optimal. I’m usually in bed by 11:30 and up by 6am. I’m going to start experimenting with some of these “sleep cycle” alarm apps to see if they’re worth the hype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What everyday thing are you better at than anyone else?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pretty good at creating efficient systems of getting things done and then sticking with that system. I’ll also continue to prove it out to make sure it’s the best solution possible. I do this with my daily commute. I’m constantly looking for the quickest way there and back. I’m never content to just stick with one route. There’s always got to be a faster way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the best advice you’ve ever received?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Energy creates energy. Potential is only realized when it becomes kinetic. It’s simple and it’s cyclical. I’m very momentum-driven and I sometimes struggle with initiation and getting things started, so this is huge for me. If I can just push past that initial opposing force of procrastination/laziness/whatever, then I can’t be stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything else you want to share with readers?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a &lt;a href=&quot;/2008/03/28/im-a-serial-archivist.html&quot;&gt;serial archivist&lt;/a&gt;. I love archiving and organizing. For Christmas this year, my father-in-law got me a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getdoxie.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Doxie&lt;/a&gt; document scanner. Coupled with &lt;a href=&quot;http://evernote.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt;, I’m using it to digitize my entire filing cabinet at some point in 2013. And I couldn’t be more excited about it. I have it all mapped out in Workflowy. And I’ll be getting to it right after I finish reorganizing my entire music collection (to better work with Subsonic) and then my entire media collection. Priorities, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 04:33:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2013/02/18/how-i-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2013/02/18/how-i-work.html</guid>
        
        <category>futures</category>
        
        <category>that-sad-and-holy-glow</category>
        
        <category>soul-driver</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How To Know You're From Kansas City</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;About nine years ago when I still lived in Ohio, two of my good friends at the time just so happened to be from Missouri and Kansas. It’s kind of a long story how they got there, but it could be said that they found a lot of our local idiosyncrasies hilarious. One day they decided to compile a  fairly smarting list of these quirky traits and emailed it to all of their Ohio friends for a good laugh (it was 2003, we emailed a lot back then). They wrote it all under the moniker “The MO-KAN Connection”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;a href=&quot;2005-08-22-108&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fairly smarting list&lt;/a&gt; --&gt;
&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll admit, I didn’t take it as kindly then as I do looking back on it now. It was pretty darn funny. But sometimes it’s not very much fun to listen to someone with an outside perspective make jokes about “your town” or “your upbringing”. I was born and raised in T-County (Tuscarawas County for long, and yea they made fun of the name too), so sometimes I just didn’t know any different. It’s good every now and then to take a look at things from a different point of view (keep this in mind as you continue reading).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cuz now, the tables have turned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s nine years later, and I’ve been living in Kansas City for over two years. Both those friends of mine have moved back to the Greater Kansas City area as well, so it’s time for me to give my own little dose of perspective on their home city/state (one of them is actually from Springfield but many of these still apply). Now granted, KC may not be as quirky as Ohio Amish country, I’ll give you that. But you guys still do some pretty crazy stuff out here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here goes, make sure to read this knowing the love behind which it was crafted. Also, read it with humility. Cuz it’s all preeeeeeetty much true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###You know you’re from Kansas City if…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You think KU vs. MU is one of the most storied rivalries in college sports.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can’t wait to take out-of-town guests to see the spectacle that is The Plaza.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You call two slabs of meat on a plain piece of white bread with a dollop of BBQ sauce and a pickle on the side “good BBQ”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You think people from Johnson County can drive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You call a trip to the Ozarks “a vacation”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You don’t think it’s weird that the “University of Kansas” and the “University of Missouri” are abbreviated KU &amp;amp; MU instead of UK &amp;amp; UM.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You don’t understand why the previous statement was included in this list.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re considering moving from the suburbs to the city just so you’ll be assured of getting Google Fiber.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You actually enjoy the ketchup &amp;amp; mustard color scheme that the Chiefs have employed since that combination of colors actually looked good together back in nineteen-NEVER.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You really did think it was “Our Time”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You place the word “highway” after the road it is referring to instead of before like the rest of America, e.g. “71 highway”, “69 highway”, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ve never heard of a drive-thru liquor store.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You could lead someone right to Truman’s birthplace like the whole of your existence depends on you knowing this information.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can name with astounding certainty which Kansas City news anchors are gay.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You defy all pronunciation rules and logic by saying the word ornery (oRn-er-y) like this: “on-ree”. (Ohio friends: Yes, that’s really how they say it)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Have you been to the Plaza yet? You’ve got to check out the Plaza.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You actually believe that you get better cell reception on your Sprint phone just because their world headquarters is in OP.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You know the best times to avoid the lines at Oklahoma Joe’s.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ve been mugged at least once.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your car has been broken into at least once.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your house has been broken into at least once.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ve never questioned why such a ridiculously asinine statement like “Rock Chalk Jayhawk” is your school’s battle cry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You know what “The Triangle” is and when to avoid it at all costs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You think that arguing with your buddies “which KC restaurant has the best BBQ in the city?” is a wise use of your time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You know exactly where The Goodfoot is playing tonight. Because it’s the exact same place they played at last week.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You will only fill up your car at a Quik Trip.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You give directions to your home by mentioning the nearest recognizable intersection, e.g. “95th &amp;amp; Metcalf”, “75th &amp;amp; Wornall”, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You consider the 6th inning sing-along to “Friends in Low Places” a fine Kauffman Stadium tradition, even though Garth Brooks isn’t from Kansas City and it JUST MAKES NO SENSE WHATSOEVER.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You think Lee’s Summit is just a short drive away.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Seriously, you haven’t been to the Plaza? We need to take you to the Plaza.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You root for the Chiefs, the Cardinals and whichever NBA team your favorite KU player is currently on. And you can’t understand why anyone would ever want to root for all the pro sports teams from just ONE city.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You call anything north of the river the “Northland”. And you REFUSE to ever go there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re not-so-secretly proud that Missouri is now considered by many to be the Meth Capital of the World.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ve pronounced it “Missour-uh” at some point in your life.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You didn’t know that Hyvee and PriceChopper weren’t nationally recognized grocery chains until you just read this sentence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You consider 90° to be a nice, breezy summer day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You regularly go on something you call “float trips” in the summer. These consist of a river, some form of flotation device and a massive amount of alcohol.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your claim to fame is that you went to the same high school as Paul Rudd, Jason Sudeikis and that guy from Modern Family.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You got a little bit too excited when Trader Joe’s opened.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You actually root for the UMKC ‘Roos at whatever sporting events they compete in. No really though, what sporting events do they compete in?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You feel that “Schlitterbahn” is a great name for a water park.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You call moving to Johnson County “selling out”. But you do it anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You actually know someone who is sending their kids through the Kansas City school district.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The highlight of a Royals game for you is the tailgating you do beforehand.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You think it’s normal to tailgate before a baseball game.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You freak out about getting your hands on some Boulevard Chocolate Ale, even though you think it tastes like liquefied Hershey bars.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Did you know Tech N9ne is from Kansas City?” “Umm, who?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You think the Chiefs are going to contend this year.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you go out of town you tell people the name of the suburb you’re from (instead of just saying you’re from “Kansas City”), as if they’ve ever heard of it!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re not really offended by this list because you’ve found yourself agreeing with so much of it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With love,&lt;br /&gt;
The T-County connection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find a copy of my buddies’ list, &lt;strong&gt;“You Know You’re From T-County If…“&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://bluestarmorning.xanga.com/11899865/item/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, on my old Xanga site.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 02:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2012/07/27/how-to-know-youre-from-kansas-city.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2012/07/27/how-to-know-youre-from-kansas-city.html</guid>
        
        <category>kc-accidental</category>
        
        <category>we-laugh-indoors</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On Leaving And Lebron</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a year now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One year ago last Wednesday, I packed up everything I could fit into a little, blue Mazda and headed west. It was one of the hardest things I’ll probably ever do in my life. Leaving my family, my friends and the only life I had known for the last 28 and half years wasn’t an easy call. But there I was, on July 6th, 2010, watching my parents fade away in my rearview as I set a course for the great unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or Kansas City, as the dot on my GPS map insisted on informing me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days later, you decided it was time to leave Ohio too. But with much bigger fanfare, naturally. Hours of news-cycle time, rampant speculation, and a much-hyped TV special were all dedicated to your big “Decision”. Most Ohioans weren’t too worried. I mean, how could you leave your &lt;em&gt;home&lt;/em&gt;? You were our “chosen one”, after all. You were the savior of Cleveland sports. The one to finally bring a championship to our hard-luck city. Fate had finally shone down upon us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was our time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We grew up with you. I, personally, saw you play three of your high school championship games at the state tournaments. I was never a particularly big basketball fan, but you had a way of igniting a passion for the game out of indifference. You turned arenas electric. We were all witnesses. And then, the impossible happened: the lowly Cavaliers lucked into taking you 1st in the draft. A once-in-a-generation talent &lt;em&gt;from our area&lt;/em&gt; coming back to &lt;em&gt;represent our area&lt;/em&gt; to the rest of the country? Northeast Ohio was abuzz. It was too good to be true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/news_poster-witness-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Quitness&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And boy, you sure knew how to put on a show. My dad bought season tickets to your games even though we lived an hour and a half away. My parents, especially, loved going to watch you play. You turned &lt;em&gt;my mom&lt;/em&gt; into a basketball fan. The games she actually let me go to with my dad will be remembered as some of the best sports experiences of my life. You turned 20,562 screaming fans into a close-knit community every night. There just wasn’t anything like it. With the game on the line, we looked to you. We knew you could “turn it on” whenever you wanted and take over the game. The rest of the team just stood and watched you work your magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/cavs-fam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cavs in my blood&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was, until, they started talking about New York. The playoff losses started mounting. The pressure on you to win now started growing. We expected you to stay, to keep fighting for your city. You &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fannation.com/truth_and_rumors/view/174990-lebrons-goal-bring-title-to-cleveland&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said it yourself&lt;/a&gt;, you weren’t going to stop until you brought home a championship to the city of Cleveland. Let ESPN talk all they want, we’d say, you wouldn’t &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; leave Ohio before you did, would you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, however, called it all along. You were going to leave. This &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; Cleveland we’re talking about, the most down-trodden sports city in the entire country. This is just the way things go here. In Ohio, we’re born defeatist. And because of it, nearly everyone in our generation is looking for a ticket out. Maybe you were just looking for your chance all along? The signs were there: the Yankees hats, your love for the Cowboys. I mean, really? You never wanted to make this your home, did you? We should have known better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first got the inkling to leave in the winter of 2009. I had just moved out on my own for the first time. My own apartment, all to myself. I was honestly just hoping to find some peace in living alone. It never came. Instead, I grew more introverted as my friends all got married or moved away. I was 27 with the specter of 30 fast approaching. The pressure was mounting to grow up fast: get married, buy a house, in whatever order you’d like. But I had exhausted all my options in Ohio. I was &lt;a href=&quot;/2010/7/5/choose-your-own-adventure.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;spinning my wheels&lt;/a&gt;. After a year of looking at possibilities: recording school in Florida, the always enticing idea of Californ-i-a, etc., I started working up the nerve it would take to actually move away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had always said I’d one day break free of the captive orbit that Ohio kept us all in. She’s an enchanter, though, and you need a darn fine reason for her to let you go. Luckily, mine drove to Ohio and met me at a youth rally I was leading praise at on New Year’s Day 2010. And she just so happened to be from Kansas City. One very option I had &lt;a href=&quot;/2010/7/5/choose-your-own-adventure.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;already been considering&lt;/a&gt;. She was my tipping point. It was then just a matter of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six months later, I was on the road to Kansas City with no job or place to stay ahead of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave my “decision” to my parents in their kitchen after one of my mom’s regular, delicious home-cooked meals. She fought back tears but said she understood. She wanted me to be happy and knew I wasn’t. I fought back tears when she asked if I’d ever consider moving back. I told my close friends in the same living room we usually talked about Jesus and drank beers. I told my niece on our back porch before she was old enough to understand what I was saying. I asked her to not forget about me when I’m gone. Those are memories I’ll always hold dear. Ones that I still can’t shake without crying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There weren’t any TV cameras, or captive audiences, or charities, or cheesy flannel shirts (well, maybe a few flannel shirts). I didn’t have the luxury of playing soft-toss with Jim Gray at some remote location in Greenwich, Connecticut (I mean, c’mon…New England?). No, there wasn’t a whole wide world of sports waiting to hear what I had decided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/lebron-decision.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dat flannel tho...&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at &lt;em&gt;least&lt;/em&gt; there was heartache. It broke my heart to leave Ohio. It broke my heart to feel like I was letting my family down by moving away. It broke my heart to know that I wouldn’t be living life beside these people anymore. That I wouldn’t be able to just drop by after work to talk and eat dinner with my parents. That I wouldn’t be going to Grandma’s after church on Sundays anymore. God had knit our hearts so close together for so many years and now our relationship would only exist on the other end of a telephone or computer screen. &lt;em&gt;That&lt;/em&gt; is heartbreaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it’s standard to write about all the favorite places that you’ll miss in your home state once you move away. But I don’t have a lot of “favorite places” in Ohio. I just have a lot of favorite &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt; in Ohio. And the times and places I’ll remember most are almost always tied to the people that I was able to share them with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know what else was heartbreaking? Watching your so-called “Decision” from the bar of a seafood restaurant on the outskirts of Kansas City. Feeling the hope of an entire region fade away on national television from 800 miles away is heartbreaking. I knew right then what the reaction would be. And I, for one, was glad I wasn’t in Ohio to see it first-hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Here we go again.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being out here for the aftermath has made me realize that no one outside of Ohio really gets it. It’s a situation that is so uniquely ours. I watched you play a preseason game here in KC while my emotions were still raw. A friend made me a sign. I wore all Cleveland garb, screamed my lungs out in derision, and embarrassed all my friends. I’m sure it was nothing like being in Cleveland for your first game back at The Q, but it sure was cathartic. ”Get over it, free agents leave,” my new KC friends would say. No, not this one. It’s bigger than that. He’s supposed to understand. He’s one of &lt;em&gt;us&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or at least we &lt;em&gt;thought&lt;/em&gt; you were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/squarespace/lebron-heated.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Heat check&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think Dan Wetzel of Yahoo Sports put the whole thing in &lt;a href=&quot;http://sports.yahoo.com/nba/news;_ylt=AoWfdJHNo5Q7zT3ZweCYfDW8vLYF?slug=dw-wetzel_cleveland_laughs_at_lebron_james_061211&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;perspective&lt;/a&gt; best:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;No city has lost like this one, not a single major professional sports championship since 1964, when the Browns won a pre-Super Bowl NFL title. You’d have to be in your mid-50s to remember it. Cleveland’s modern sports memories are defined in short terms, as if elaborating is just too painful: The Drive, The Fumble, The Shot, The Move and, of course, The Decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You want collapses? The 1997 World Series is as bad as anything the Cubs or Red Sox ever dealt with. It’s just this city doesn’t have the media poets to chronicle it like Chicago or Boston. You want the true gut punch? Their beloved Browns moved to Baltimore only to finally get their act together and win a Super Bowl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And then there was this, LeBron James, the local kid from Akron, the one who claimed he understood your heartache, the one you defended for years, the one that was finally going to deliver sporting glory. He bails for some fair-weather sports town and an arena full of white-covered chairs with pretty people who can’t even be bothered to watch the game while it’s going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did it break your heart to leave Ohio? I know it didn’t break your heart to leave Cleveland. The way you left tells us that much. Your big Lithuanian friend &lt;em&gt;who didn’t even grow up in America&lt;/em&gt;, let alone Cleveland, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.waitingfornextyear.com/2010/08/zydrunas-ilgauskas-thanks-fans-in-sunday-morning-ad/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;showed everyone&lt;/a&gt; how you leave a beloved city with class: “I…hope you realize that Cleveland will always be home to me.” You’d do well to take notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is, we glossed over your arrogance. The showboating, the posturing, the egotism, the chalk toss. It was downplayed because you were a “hometown” boy. We saw it and just laughed it off. And that’s on us. But now, it’s on you. We’ve grieved, but we’re &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P3pbLyHCOCo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;moving on&lt;/a&gt;. Akron might take you back, but Ohio never will. You’ve taken your place in the long list of dark spots in Cleveland’s sports history. Did you really envision it turning out any differently? If you really were ashamed of claiming Ohio as your home, you wouldn’t have to worry about it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ohio is ashamed of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a year and I think I’ve finally come to terms with leaving Ohio. I might’ve just come to terms with you leaving too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t blame you for wanting to leave Ohio. I mean, look at me, I left too. No, I blame you for the way you left. And that’s coming from a guy who tried his best to leave the right way. I gave my job a two-month notice. I got my affairs in order. I wanted to give people time to adjust. But really, I think I was the one who needed the adjustment time. It was a transition. I needed time to grieve and let people grieve. You don’t just pull the rug out from under people’s feet. Not when the particular people you’re hoodwinking have had such a sorry history of similar close-calls and let-downs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve built up so many defense mechanisms over the years as Ohioans, ones that you seemed to have deliberately played into. We have it in our blood to be confidently optimistic and then curse the wind when the same thing happens &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cleveland_Browns_relocation_controversy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;over&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1997_World_Series&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;over&lt;/a&gt; again. We build up just enough hope so that there’s a substantial enough amount to get dashed away later. Sarcasm has become engrained in our way of life. We’re cocky to the Steelers fans, to the Celtics fans, to the Yankees &amp;amp; Red Sox fans and then just fall back to “Well, there’s always next year!” when the cycle continues. Whole &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.waitingfornextyear.com/2011/07/hurry-up-wait-and-be-patient-with-browns/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;websites&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.clevelandfrowns.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;internet followings&lt;/a&gt; have grown out of this effort in futility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe me, I wanted to leave all that negativity behind too. But leaving has given me a new love for my home state. It’s that fond love that grows with distance. And I bet it’s growing in you now too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirteen hours on the road by yourself gives you just enough time to get excited about what you’re doing, then doubt what you’re doing, and then get excited all over again. My mood swings on that never-ending drive through the Plains were most likely dictated by the ups and downs of the wide array of music I had put into playlists for the long journey out. Luckily, it kept me distracted just long enough from thinking about how I honestly didn’t know where I would be staying when I got out to Kansas City. I just knew that it’s where I needed to be. A few rather kind folks decided to take me in. I stayed on my best friend’s couch for a night. And then transferred my meager belongings into the den of a house that belonged to three guys I barely knew. They graciously allowed me to stay there until I landed a job in my new home city. That stay would last for just under three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t know it then, but I had just happened into one of the most amazing group of friends that I’ve ever been apart of. Yes, I had to make the heart-rending decision to leave my family and friends back in Ohio. But I met, dated, and am going to marry the girl of my dreams out here in KC in three months. She wound up being a pretty good reason to leave Ohio. The price was steep, but I’d say it was a fairly even trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, can you say the same thing? Was it worth it? I’ll be honest, I rooted for you to lose. And just about all of Ohio was darn happy when you did. Even if you would have pulled out some late-game magic like you always seemed to do for us, would it have been as fulfilling? Wouldn’t it have been &lt;em&gt;that much sweeter&lt;/em&gt; if you were winning it all for Cleveland? Wouldn’t that be a much greater cause? It sure looks like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/07/11/lebron-james-popularity-all-time-low_n_894819.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rest of America&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://sports.espn.go.com/nba/news/story?id=5575810&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;thinks so&lt;/a&gt;. But hey, you made your choice. And I made mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it turned out to be the best one I’ve ever made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“All the people that was rooting on me to fail, at the end of the day they have to wake up tomorrow and have the same life that they had before they woke up today,” James said. “They have the same personal problems they had today. I’m going to continue to live the way I want to live and continue to do the things that I want to do with me and my family and be happy with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“They can get a few days or a few months or whatever the case may be on being happy about not only myself, but the Miami Heat not accomplishing their goal. But they have to get back to the real world at some point.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, now &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; have to get back to the real world. We already live here. The real world of making a decision and having to stick with it. There’s no turning back. It’s I-70 westbound straight into the setting sun with only pictures of your family and the hope of what lies on the other side to keep you going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But whatever you have to say to help you sleep at night. You’ve made your bed. You chose and you lost. But hey, coming from Ohio you should be pretty familiar with that empty feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, well, there’s always next year.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 03:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2011/07/12/on-leaving-and-lebron.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2011/07/12/on-leaving-and-lebron.html</guid>
        
        <category>bloodbuzz-ohio</category>
        
        <category>fambly</category>
        
        <category>all-is-a-game</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Facebook Is The Mark Of The Beast</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I mean, is there really any doubt?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know one thing, I used to write things on the internet. Sometimes they were interesting, sometimes they were complete drivel. But the key was, I wrote them. I sat down at my computer, I opened a blog post window and I wrote.
These days, I’m more likely to open a rapid succession of Facebook and Twitter windows and read things other people have written. Some of them interesting, some complete drivel. I still write, but it’s more fragments and pieces of thoughts than what I would have otherwise have formed into complete phrases within a blog post a few years back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each tweet, each status update have given me a sense of completion, but they’re just a taste. They’re nothing like that thrill of hitting the “publish” button on a long-form work that you’ve given serious thought and contemplation to. I’m sure it’s somewhere near what a novelist feels when they hit the return key at the end of a completed chapter. It’s that sense of fear in knowing your thoughts will be read, but also, that satisfaction in knowing you’ve created something and you’ve put yourself out there to be critiqued. And well, that counts for something, doesn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this is a post about how I haven’t posted. And my struggle to figure out why. I’ve had an idea of something to write for going on a year now. And I just haven’t written it. This would have bothered me a few years ago. Back then, I &lt;a href=&quot;/tag/xanga&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wrote something&lt;/a&gt; just about every day. It was more of a journal of my day’s events than anything. But I took great care to fashion each post. I designed the site with great attention to detail. I took a lot of pride in my silly, little Xanga page. And now I laugh a lot when I go back and read through it. But the point is, it’s still there. You can still go and read all the thoughts, emotions and events of my life for the span of well over three years. It’s riveting material, let me forewarn you. Wikipedia rabbit-trails have nothing on my Xanga site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also a post about how I’m not quitting Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I’ve read blog posts about this sort of phenomena before. And usually all of them end with the author resigning himself to quitting Facebook/Twitter and only posting on their blogs from here on out. That’s great and all, except for the mere fact that no one will read anything you’ll write from here on out. There are a few exceptions, but on the whole everyone looks to Facebook to see what’s going on in their world. Facebook (and Twitter to a lesser extent) has become the only online social hub. We’ve all taken it’s mark. There is no socializing outside it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a bit drastic, I know. But it’s the future, and I’ve accepted that. It grieves me a little that sites like Xanga aren’t the social epicenter anymore. But I get why they died, they weren’t instant enough. They had a lazy pace to them. But I think it was that lazy pace that made it easier for deliberate thinkers like me to keep stride with our quicker-witted online peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet is just getting so fast. And I can’t keep up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I log on, read about everyone else’s day, maybe type a few words and then close up shop. When I had my Xanga, life was the only thing that kept me from updating it. These days, it’s the internet that keeps me from updating about my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose I could just resolve myself to write more. And I’m going to do my best (starting with that post I’ve been thinking up for about a year). After all, my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birkman.com/birkmanMethod/whatIsTheBirkmanMethod.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Birkman report&lt;/a&gt; told me that, above all, I’m a “Literary”-type, and that I’m not completely fulfilled unless I’m consistently writing or doing something close to it. The fact remains, though: the internet has changed. And so too, must my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to anyone who has stuck around to read my infrequent writings on this site, I certainly appreciate your patience. I truly hope to get to a post of more substance shortly (it’s relevancy window is closing rapidly).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then…completion is just a click away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. - In this same online writing vein, a few friends and I have started an online newspaper detailing the insignificant minutiae of our daily lives. It’s more for us than you but it’s a good time regardless. It’s called “The 6th Degree”, and you can check it out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.the-6th-degree.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;######&lt;em&gt;Note: This was originally posted on an old Squarespace blog of mine. Most of the references, links and jokes are probably dead.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 02:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2011/07/06/facebook-is-the-mark-of-the-beast.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2011/07/06/facebook-is-the-mark-of-the-beast.html</guid>
        
        <category>that-sad-and-holy-glow</category>
        
        <category>wolf-am-i</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top 10 Of '10</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I’ve posted a year-end best of list. This is due mostly to the fact that I haven’t listened to 10 albums in a year that I liked enough to put in a year-end best of list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, thankfully, I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tops:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Violet (The National) -&lt;/strong&gt; I’m consistently blown away by the stuff these guys are coming up with record after record. They’re just consistently great. And that’s no easy task (re: Midlake, below). “Boxer” was phenomenal and somehow they were able to top themselves again. They also recorded my new favorite “Ohio” song. I’m sure they’ll be pleased to know.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Age of Adz/All Delighted People EP (Sufjan Stevens) -&lt;/strong&gt; It wouldn’t be a best-of list by Ryan Straits without an appearance by Sufjan. I’ll be honest, it took me a while to get into both of these records (I packaged them together because they came out so close to each other), but once I did I couldn’t get enough. It also helped that I saw him perform these live soon after the albums released. Epic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Promise (Bruce Springsteen) -&lt;/strong&gt; “Darkness on the Edge of Town” is probably my favorite Boss album, so an album of B-Sides recorded during the “Darkness” sessions is naturally going to be right up my alley. And the Boss DOES NOT disappoint. The revamped version of “Racing In the Street” is worth the Deluxe Box set price, alone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go (Jonsi) -&lt;/strong&gt; It’s Sigur Ros on speed. And really, they were in need of a lil pep-up.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brothers (The Black Keys) -&lt;/strong&gt; In retrospect, I should have been a bigger fan of a band that hails from Akron, Ohio. Spoiler alert: I am now.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shame, Shame (Dr. Dog) -&lt;/strong&gt; Not as great of an album as their past two releases but I’ll take sub-standard Dr. Dog any day over your best Justin Bieber. Srsly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Suburbs (Arcade Fire) -&lt;/strong&gt; The first 3 songs? AWESOME. The rest? Ehhh. Doesn’t have the re-playability that “Funeral” and “Neon Bible” had. However, I would listen to “Rococo” over and over if it meant I got to see these guys live sometime this year.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walking On A Dream (Empire of the Sun) -&lt;/strong&gt; They’re fun, and different, and great to workout to. See, it really doesn’t take much to crack my top 10.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infinite Arms (Band of Horses) -&lt;/strong&gt; Nice ‘n easy listening. That’s pretty much it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saint Bartlett (Damien Jurado) -&lt;/strong&gt; Sadly, I was never as into ol’ Damien as much my buddy Dave was growing up. However, I’m into this new record. Maybe now I’ll go back and re-listen to some of those older albums Dave kept yapping about. Maybe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friends:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tadaima (The Non) -&lt;/strong&gt; I had the chance to see these guys twice over the summer while I was mobile and unemployed. There’s really no comparison for their live show. Seriously, a must-see.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wanderer, O Wanderer EP (Come Wind) -&lt;/strong&gt; Come Wind is comprised of some very dear friends of mine. I knew they were good, but I didn’t know they were THIS good. I’d be lying if I said this album didn’t stay in my car stereo for quite a few weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holy Spirits EP (State Bird) -&lt;/strong&gt; They seem to reinvent themselves with every new record. Every time I think I’m not gonna like the new sound. And every time I’m proven wrong.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Badlands (Chris Staples)/Future Paths (Discover America) -&lt;/strong&gt; I now live in the same city that Chris &amp;amp; I got robbed at gunpoint together in. I cry nightly in the shower; he keeps putting out solid records. (Editors note: Chris Staples = Discover America)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Honorable Mention:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Invented (Jimmy Eat World) -&lt;/strong&gt; They seem to be hearkening back a few albums with this latest release. I had written them off but if their next album continues in this trend I might need to write them back on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I Had A Hi-Fi (Nada Surf) -&lt;/strong&gt; I pretty much like most anything these guys come out with (all the way back to “Popular”). I felt a little hoodwinked, though, when I found out (after several listens) that this was just a covers album. Originals &amp;gt; covers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mines (Menomena) -&lt;/strong&gt; Before this album I could point to one Menomena song that I liked. Now I can point to a whole album.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Beautiful Dark Twisted Fantasy (Kanye West) -&lt;/strong&gt; My quasi-secret Kanye fandom continues. He may be an idiot, but he’s got more talent in his pinkie finger than Taylor Swift has in…well, you get the idea.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most Disappointing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Courage of Others (Midlake) -&lt;/strong&gt; I really, really, REALLY wanted to like this album. But I expected a heckuva lot more from a band that forces us to wait 4 years between releases. I’d rather just listen to “Head Home” on repeat until they release their next one.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forgiveness Rock Record (Broken Social Scene) -&lt;/strong&gt; The sum used to be greater than it’s parts. Now its struggling to get all it’s parts back just to record a new album. They’re officially too big for their britches.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Chorus Of Storytellers (The Album Leaf) -&lt;/strong&gt; Once upon a time, The Album Leaf were the only ones that sounded like The Album Leaf. Now, everyone does. Time for a reinvention, Mr. LaValle.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Congratulations (MGMT) -&lt;/strong&gt; “What the #$%&amp;amp; is this?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoyed! A new entry coming soon-ish…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;######&lt;em&gt;Note: This was originally posted on an old Squarespace blog of mine. Most of the references, links and jokes are probably dead.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2010 23:39:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2010/12/29/top-10-of-10.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2010/12/29/top-10-of-10.html</guid>
        
        <category>dad-rock</category>
        
        <category>exit-music-for-a-film</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ugly Christmas Sweater</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, while I’ve had a blog post idea in my head for running on 3 months now, the urge to sit down and actually write it out just hasn’t been able to crack my air-tight schedule these last few months. I’m sad that this blog has gone by the wayside, but working 55-hour weeks at my new job, spending time w/ my girlfriend, flying home to Ohio for holidays, and working on the project that is the subject of this post has taken up the lion’s share of my time recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aforementioned project, &lt;a href=&quot;http://uglychristmassweater.bandcamp.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ugly Christmas Sweater&lt;/a&gt;, consists of a few traditional &amp;amp; original Christmas songs that my roommate, Diego Chi, myself and two of our friends (Cayla Waller &amp;amp; Rachel Devilbiss) put together in the weeks before Christmas. It was a blast to write and record music again, especially apart of a group. I hope to do much more of it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy, and that you and yours had yourself a merry, little Christmas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;&quot; src=&quot;http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1151047165/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://uglychristmassweater.bandcamp.com/album/ugly-christmas-sweater&quot;&gt;Ugly Christmas Sweater by Ugly Christmas Sweater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;######&lt;em&gt;Note: This was originally posted on an old Squarespace blog of mine. Most of the references, links and jokes are probably dead.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2010 02:49:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2010/12/27/ugly-christmas-sweater.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2010/12/27/ugly-christmas-sweater.html</guid>
        
        <category>dad-rock</category>
        
        <category>its-hard-to-find-a-friend</category>
        
        <category>soul-driver</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Adventure Continues...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been nearly 2 months since I moved to Kansas City. Much has happened. I hope to bring you a full-featured update in the shape of a long-form post within the next few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then, here is a glimpse of a few of the things I’ve been working on while I’m still unemployed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yeameneither.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;yeameneither.com&lt;/a&gt; - A fun, little website based on a Twitter trend (#yeameneither) that my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://travisgeary.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Travis&lt;/a&gt; and I started for the heck of it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.Com/dctalkraps&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DCTalk Raps&lt;/a&gt; - What, you haven’t heard of DC Talk Raps yet? Oh, you will. A DC Talk rap in your Twitter feed everyday? Are you kidding me? Life just doesn’t get better than that.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://godateventide.Tumblr.Com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;God At Eventide&lt;/a&gt; - I bought this old devotional book from 1965 from a thrift store here in KC after the note scribbled on the first page intrigued me: “To my sweetheart of 30 years who is making my life one of thrills and joys together as we walk upward toward our eternal home. - Your Sweetheart”. I decided to start posting each day’s devotion as I read them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh yes. And I’ve also found myself a lady friend. The coolest girl I know on either side of the Mississippi. So far, KC, you’ve done well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come soon, friends!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;######&lt;em&gt;Note: This was originally posted on an old Squarespace blog of mine. Most of the references, links and jokes are probably dead.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 16:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2010/09/03/the-adventure-continues.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2010/09/03/the-adventure-continues.html</guid>
        
        <category>kc-accidental</category>
        
        <category>we-laugh-indoors</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Choose Your Own Adventure</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Or, “Leaving/Staying Pt. 2”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are words I’ve been meaning to write for a little over three months now. Unfortunately, they haven’t formed themselves into complete sentences until tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of my fondest memories as a child revolved around the regular trips my mom took my sisters and I on to the quaint, local library of our little town. The reason for the trips were usually school-based in nature, but the undoubted highlight for my pre-adolescent mind was picking up the latest offering from the keenly-titled “&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Choose_Your_Own_Adventure&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Choose Your Own Adventure&lt;/a&gt;” series of books. I devoured every copy I came across within mere hours. I became engrossed in every turn of every story and was incredibly curious about &lt;a href=&quot;http://flowingdata.com/2009/08/11/choose-your-own-adventure-most-likely-youll-die/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;every possible conclusion&lt;/a&gt; that the book could lead me to. So much so, that I think my ardent wonder might have developed into something of a character flaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because somewhere along the line, I started bookmarking every decision I came to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s right, I bookmarked every single decision and when that decision ultimately led to some grotesque demise, which it was &lt;a href=&quot;http://flowingdata.com/2009/08/11/choose-your-own-adventure-most-likely-youll-die/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;most likely to&lt;/a&gt;, I retraced my steps back until I made the right decision. Now, i’m sure most of the kids reading “choose your own adventure” books along with me in the early 90’s did something along the same lines. After all, to get the most bang for your buck (or my 2-week library checkout, rather) you had to go through quite a few redo’s. I might have just taken those redo’s a bit too far by redoing every single decision I made until I came across the best possible outcome. Those of you who are familiar with “choose your own adventure” know this was no easy task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s safe to say that I’ve had a fairly enlightening year. In fact, I may have learned more things about myself in the past year or so than I have in any other combination of years in my life. It’s possible that some of these things were readily seen and known by those around me, but it’s taken me roughly 28 years to let them sink in. You shouldn’t have to wait so many years to learn so many truths about yourself. I feel like God should sit us down the moment we’re born and fill us in, “These are the things you’ll be good at, son, do them and do them often.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess maybe we need that time, though. We need to go the long way around. Maybe we couldn’t handle a deluge of revelation all at once. We need that slow succession of seconds, that stacking up of lessons over time. We need maturity to do it’s faithful work, bit by bit, everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I’m saying is it isn’t fair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what have I learned? Well first off, I’ve learned that on the whole, I lack motivation. All this reading about motivation and I honestly don’t have much to speak of. I did at one time, I know that. Back when I was young and reckless. Back when I had only the next four years of my life planned out. When I set broad, mountain-esque goals for myself but put no realistic structure in place for how to go about reaching them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So naturally, I sputtered out. I hit a dead-end. I was stagnant. Breathing, yes. Subsisting, sure. But not moving. Not working towards something. Not heading anywhere. Those who know me best would say I was “spinning my wheels” or “stuck in pause”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I was waiting on something. Waiting on something to happen. Waiting on opportunities? Waiting on God? I guess. I suppose I was stuck at a bookmark. But one key lesson I’ve learned from all this reading/revelation is that we should take stock of the things God has given us. The talents, the gifts, the abilities, the connections, the friends, the family. Whatever we have that is supernatural. Whatever is divinely ours and no one else’s. And we need to use them. And use them now. Appreciate them severely. We can’t wait for something we think should be coming around the bend. Because, honestly, it may never come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, it was time for a drastic decision to be made. It was high time to awake out of sleep. Time to do something because now is the time to get something done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://read.ly/2Kgs7.3.KJV&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Why sit we here til we die?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, that’s where my previously referenced, childhood character flaw begins to set in. I fear commitment. I’ve always been indecisive and figured that it’s just how I am. But I believe now that it goes deeper. I fear whittling down options until I’m locked into one singular path. Because then, there’s no looking back. There’s no redo. There’s no backspace or CTRL+ALT+Delete. It’s just me, my decision, and God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to own it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I hate that. I hate not having options. I pack twice as many clothes as I need on a trip because I like to have options. I don’t like making concrete plans because then I can’t change my mind later. I resist releasing music that I’ve recorded because then I won’t have the option of editing it later. I’ve even passed up relationships because something in me says that I have to hold out for something better.
And I’ve stayed put in the town I was born in because I know my options for living elsewhere will always be limitless. They’ll always be out there. And they’ll always be an excuse for not living an adventure now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the great philosopher, Pedro the Lion, once said, “It’s good to have options”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point my decision became more than just my decision. It left the scale of the common, ordinary “What will I eat for breakfast?” minutia to a whole other stratosphere. The decision took on a life of it’s own. I would say that it’s possible that I was not even the one making it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just knew that something needed to change and it would have to be soon. So I began heeding my advice. I began taking stock of the things God had given me. The relationships, the talents, the gifts, the abilities, the connections; I started making a list. Started weighing pro’s and con’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And increasingly the lot began to fall to Kansas City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ties to Kansas City have been oddly vast over the years. From the youth camps I led worship at in high school to the post-college years when I toured through there as apart of an indie-rock band. There’s the close friends who have recently moved there to the recently-acquainted friends who have lived there all their lives. Something was beginning to pull me in a westerly-facing direction. And that something was not me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I prayed. And prayed. And sought counsel. I fasted a month from Facebook. I wanted to know for certain that this something wasn’t me or some airy notion I picked up from someone else. I wanted to make sure that God knew what he was doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because moving to Kansas City sounds completely crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving a very good job with no certain means of employment waiting for you in a foreign state is crazy. Quitting a worship band that you love playing on week-in-and-week-out is crazy. Moving 13 hours away from the only friends you’ve known and the dear family that you’ve come to love more and more with every passing year is absolutely crazy. Leaving everything you’ve ever known is crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I think I’m ready for crazy. I think I need crazy right now. I think what I’ve needed most of all to push me past this rut in life is a fresh step of faith. I’m two years from 30. My hairline has begun receding (with no hope of it moving in the opposite direction) and my body certainly aches more than it used to. I need to get out and live now or I never will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’ve needed most is an adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An adventure of my own choosing. A decision that I can’t bookmark. An option that I can’t go back and change. A single point that I must cross and not turn back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I am doing just that. I don’t know exactly what I’ll be doing there. Or even where I’ll be living. But I do know that it’s now after 2:00am on Monday, July 5th, 2010 and I am moving to Kansas City tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there is no turning back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will you choose to sit here until you die? Turn to page 54.&lt;br /&gt;
Or will you choose to get up and live? Turn to page 73.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s interesting how you sometimes have to leave home before you can ask difficult questions, how the questions never come up in the room you grew up in, in the town in which you were born. It’s funny how you can’t ask difficult questions in a familiar place, how you have to stand back a few feet and see things in a new way before you realize nothing that is happening to you is normal. - Donald Miller&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;######&lt;em&gt;Note: This was originally posted on an old Squarespace blog of mine. Most of the references, links and jokes are probably dead.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 06:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2010/07/05/choose-your-own-adventure.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2010/07/05/choose-your-own-adventure.html</guid>
        
        <category>rehearsals-for-departure</category>
        
        <category>kc-accidental</category>
        
        <category>the-promised-land</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Motivation/Hesitation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I know I promised to write more. And I haven’t. But I fall back on my previous promise to not spend as much time on the internet as my sole defense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- break --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of wise uses of my time, I’ve been reading a few stellar books lately. Last fall, my interest was piqued on the topic of motivation and relatedly, of success, by a really superb &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ted.com/talks/dan_pink_on_motivation.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TED Talk&lt;/a&gt; I happened upon. So piqued was I, in fact, that I decided to fork over nearly $25 for a newly released hard-cover copy of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Drive-Surprising-Truth-About-Motivates/dp/1594488843/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1269310552&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;speaker’s own book&lt;/a&gt; on the subject while I was on vacation. I then spent additional monies on another book I had been hearing a lot of buzz about, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Outliers-Story-Success-Malcolm-Gladwell/dp/0316017922/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1269309665&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Outliers”&lt;/a&gt; by Malcolm Gladwell. Both were excellent, informative reads and I would highly recommend both to anyone as intrigued by these subjects as I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In looking into all this, I was most interested in learning just what it is that seems to determine our success in life, specifically, is it more influenced by our own motivation/hard work/grit/determination/etc. (as we are all told growing up, i.e. The epitome of “The American Dream”) or more by the amount, or lack, of opportunities we are afforded? As a person who believes wholeheartedly in the practice of temperance/moderation, I know the argument can be made that a healthy balance of both will undoubtedly get you where you want to be in life. I think it’s a fair point, but I wanted to dive deeper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In “Outliers” (which I read first), Gladwell talks mostly about the unique circumstances behind some of the most successful people we know of today. A few examples: Bill Gates. He was exposed at a very early age to one of the first commercially available computers. He had the opportunity to spend many, many hours working at it due to a combination of exceptional events. He also proved (many times over, actually) the infamous &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Outliers_(book)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;10,000 hour rule&lt;/a&gt;, Which is said to be the threshold for obtaining mastery (the 2nd book discusses this concept further).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Beatles also helped to prove the 10,000 hour rule. Before they hit it big, they spent several years playing seedy clubs around Hamburg, Germany. By Gladwell’s calculations, they played roughly 10,000 hours together as a group before their American invasion. These unique “practice” years undoubtedly honed their sound, their songwriting, and most would say greatly contributed to their success later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with “Outliers”, the conclusion can be drawn that yes, success is determined by hard work and motivation to succeed, but without favorable opportunities to seize hold of, the hard work is essentially meaningless. We can scratch out a living, sure, but we can’t scratch out true success without a few “lucky” breaks first, i.e. no one truly pulls themselves up by their own bootstraps. We need a few little “nudges” to help us on our way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take that, ‘Merica.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel pink’s “Drive” (the TED Talker’s book), expanded more on the idea of motivation and just what it is that actually drives us. He mainly pitted outdated notions of extrinsic motivators (i.e. “carrots &amp;amp; sticks”) against newer findings on intrinsic motivators (our own internal drives) and proposed that there is a mismatch between what science knows and what businesses actually do. Specifically, the science that he cites proves that we are much more likely to respond better to our own internal drives when encouraged properly then to external drives from bosses, supervisors, etc. He also posits that humans are needing “management” less and less to prosper in business today. Mostly because management is a man-made concept. It’s technology, not something that’s replicated in nature, so thus, it will eventually become outdated. And it may already be for most of today’s current job functions. It may have worked well in the 20th century for mostly left-brained, mechanical tasks but it doesn’t make sense when dealing with more 21st century, right-brained, out-of-the-box type problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He further breaks down our internal drive into the three things that all humans desire in life: autonomy, mastery and purpose. We all want to direct our own lives, we all want to be great at what we do and we all want to be apart of something bigger than ourselves. No-brainers, really. So why don’t our jobs and businesses play to these inherent motivators that we all already have? As pink states, if you want compliance, you manage, or dare I say, micro-manage. But if you want engagement, you encourage self-direction. We are our own greatest motivator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we already know this, don’t we? I think it’s innate in all of us. If you’re not so easily convinced, I would simply point to all those who dream of starting up their own businesses or who want to work for themselves someday. This is the land of entrepreneurship after all, isn’t it? So why aren’t companies adopting more of these ideas into how they approach their employees? It’s a fair question. The data proves that productivity and general employee well-being goes up and turnover goes down when they do. And as a result, many more companies are implementing some of the practices that pink discusses in this book. It’s the wave of the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And something worth pondering, that’s for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I was planning to get more into how these ideas were showing up in my life personally (or how frustrated I am that they’re not more of a reality in my life) but alas, this post has drug on long enough. I’ll divulge more at a later date, I promise…I hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up on my reading list:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Freakonomics-Economist-Explores-Hidden-Everything/dp/006073132X&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Freakonomics”&lt;/a&gt;. Yeah, I’ve kind of turned into a geek for these sorts of books now. But this one was a Goodwill find. No more new release, hard-cover copies at full price, thank you very much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thank you very much for stopping by and reading this latest winding entry of mine. May the next post make its way to your screen much speedier than the last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;######&lt;em&gt;Note: This was originally posted on an old Squarespace blog of mine. Most of the references, links and jokes are probably dead.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2010 03:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2010/03/27/motivation-hesitation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ryanstraits.com/2010/03/27/motivation-hesitation.html</guid>
        
        <category>time-is-a-bird</category>
        
        <category>soul-driver</category>
        
        <category>land-of-hope-and-dreams</category>
        
        <category>squarespace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
